most people will experience tremendous
大多数人在开始生酮饮食后
reductions in anxiety within 3 Days To 3
3天到3周内，焦虑症状就会显著减轻。
fact we did a study where patients with
事实上，我们做过一项研究，让患有
bipolar disorder major depression or
双相情感障碍、重度抑郁症或
schizophrenia tried the ketogenic diet
精神分裂症的患者尝试生酮饮食，结果
and 43% achieved clinical remission from
43%的患者达到了
their chronic mental illness and 64% of
慢性精神疾病的临床缓解，64%的
them left un less psychiatric medication
患者减少了精神科药物的用量，
because it improves the balance of
因为生酮饮食改善了
chemicals in the brain but the question
大脑中化学物质的平衡。但问题
is what's causing those chemical
是，究竟是什么导致了这些化学物质的
imbalances in the first place and so
失衡？
let's start there Dr Georgia e is a
让我们从这里开始。乔治亚·E博士是一位
Harvard train psychiatrist who
哈佛大学毕业的精神科医生，
specializes in nutritional science and
专攻营养科学和
mental health she was one of the first
心理健康。她是最早
psychiatrists to offer nutrition-based
提出以营养为基础的
approaches as an alternative to
疗法作为
psychiatric medications to optimize
精神科药物的替代方案，以优化
brain function and enhance performance
大脑功能和提高表现的精神科医生之一。
people need to know how powerful
人们需要了解
nutrition strategies can be for the
营养策略对
brain because if you're feeding at the
大脑的强大作用，因为如果饮食方式
wrong way things will go wrong and
错误，就会出现问题。
that's exactly what happened to me my
这正是我曾经的经历。我
health was declining in my early 40s in
在40岁出头的时候健康状况就开始恶化，
ways that is true for a lot of my
我的很多
patients chronic fatigue and IBS being
患者也面临着同样的问题：慢性疲劳、肠易激综合征、焦虑
really anxious and depressed and so I
和抑郁。所以我
did all kinds of tests they said there's
尝试了各种方法。 做了很多检查，他们说我
nothing wrong of course there was
没问题，当然，肯定有
something wrong so I instinctively
问题。所以我本能地
started experimenting with my diet and
开始尝试调整饮食，最终
the diet that I ended up on was
我采用的饮食方式与
healthy for us it should theoretically
我们通常被告知的健康饮食截然相反，理论上应该会
kill me but it result every single one
要了我的命，但它却缓解了
of my symptoms and so I studied for
我所有的症状。因此，我花了数
years learning things about food that
年时间研究食物，了解
most people don't know and which foods
大多数人不知道的知识，以及哪些食物
contain the nutrients the brain needs or
含有大脑所需的营养，哪些
the ingredients that damage the brain
成分会损害大脑。我
and found three principles of nutrition
发现了三个营养原则，
they can help you in ways no medicine
它们能以药物无法企及的方式帮助你，
can as well as improved mood memory
改善情绪、记忆力、注意力、
concentration stamina productivity so
耐力和工作效率。
let's unpack that
让我们来详细探讨一下。
this has always blown my mind a little
这总是让我有点震惊：
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常收听我们节目的听众中，有53%还没有订阅。
show so could I ask you for a favor
所以，
before we start if you like the show and
在我们开始之前，能否请你们帮个忙？如果你喜欢我们的节目，
you like what we do here and you want to
喜欢我们在这里所做的一切，并且想要
support us the free simple way that you
支持我们，最简单的方法就是
can do just that is by hitting the
点击“
Subscribe button and my commitment to
订阅”按钮。我向
you is if you do that then I'll do
你们承诺，如果你们订阅了，
everything in my power me and my team to
我和我的团队将竭尽全力，
make sure that this show is better for
确保每周的节目都能为你们带来更好的体验。
your feedback we'll find the guest that
您的反馈对我们非常重要，我们会找到您
you want me to speak to and we'll
希望我采访的嘉宾，并
continue to do what we do thank you so
继续做好我们的工作。非常感谢
Dr Georg
Georg
Eid how do you define what what it is
Eid博士，您如何定义
you
您的工作内容？
do I am a psychiatrist specializing in
我是一名精神科医生，专攻
nutritional and metabolic Psychiatry so
营养和代谢精神病学，也就是
how food affects the brain and how food
食物如何影响大脑，食物如何
affects brain metabolism and how brain
影响大脑代谢，以及大脑
metabolism affects our mental health
代谢如何影响我们的心理健康。
this is a fairly new phrase metabolic
代谢精神病学是一个相当新的术语，
Psychiatry am I right in thinking that
我的理解对吗？是的，
yes it's a really it's a very new field
它确实是一个非常新的领域，
and really exciting field uh the the
也是一个非常令人兴奋的领域。这个
term itself was coined by Dr Shabani
术语是由斯坦福大学的代谢精神病学家Shabani Sethi博士提出的，
Stanford University and maybe five years
大概五年前，
ago or so maybe a little longer than
也许更久一点。
that so it's a very very new field it's
所以它是一个非常非常新的领域，
even newer than the other exciting New
甚至比精神病学中另一个令人兴奋的新
Field in Psychiatry which is nutritional
领域——营养
Psychiatry and so and this is a really
精神病学——还要新。对于精神科医生来说，这是一个非常
exciting time to be a
激动人心的时代，对于
empowering time for people with mental
患有精神健康问题的人来说，这也是一个激动人心、充满希望、充满力量的时代，
health conditions because we're finally
因为我们终于
able to explore um root causes the real
能够探索…… 嗯，真正的
root causes the deeper root causes of
根本原因，更深层次的
mental health conditions that go beyond
心理健康问题根源，远不止
things like what we're told all the time
我们一直被告知的
which are these mysterious chemical
那些神秘的化学物质
imbalances you know that need to be
失衡，这些都需要
addressed with medication We Now
用药物来解决。我们现在
understand that the real drivers the
明白，
primary drivers of mental health
心理健康
conditions are inflammation of the brain
问题的真正驱动因素，主要驱动因素是大脑炎症，也就是
something called oxidative stress which
所谓的氧化应激。这就是
is why we're always told to eat more
为什么我们总是被告知要多吃
anti oxidants and insulin resistance or
抗氧化剂，以及胰岛素抵抗或
pre-diabetes which is now affects more
糖尿病前期。现在，
than 90% of Americans in your work you
超过90%的美国人都受到糖尿病前期的影响。在你的作品中，你经常
talk a lot about the ketogenic diet why
谈到生酮饮食。为什么它
is that so prevalent in your work was
在你的作品中如此盛行？
the ketogenic diet energizes the brain
生酮饮食能以不同的方式为大脑提供能量，
differently so it it really
从而从
fundamentally changes the brain's
根本上改变大脑的
operating system so when you switch from
操作系统。当你从
a high
高
carbohydrate High insulin diet to a low
碳水化合物、高胰岛素的饮食转变为低
insulin which is us a low carbohydrate
胰岛素的饮食（也就是我们所说的低碳水化合物
diet ketogenic
饮食，即生酮饮食）时，
cells uh receive
细胞获取
energy the the mixture of fuels that
能量的方式，
they're using changes and that has
它们使用的燃料混合物，都会发生改变，这对
pathway inside of that cell so it is as
细胞内的几乎所有通路，几乎所有化学通路都会产生深远的影响。这就
though you are fundamentally changing
好比你以非常健康的方式从根本上改变了
the brain's operating system uh in very
大脑的操作系统，使
healthy ways that allow not brain cells
脑细胞能够更好地运作。
not only to work better but for uh but
不仅是为了更好地工作，也是
for brain cells to heal so the longer
为了促进脑细胞修复。所以，
you stay on a ketogenic diet the more
你坚持生酮饮食的时间越长，
healing the more brain healing can take
脑细胞的修复效果就越好。
place and what is your sort of academic
你的学术
and career experience what's that can
和职业经历是怎样的？
you run me through that sort of timeline
你能跟我简要介绍一下你的时间线吗？好的，
yeah so I uh got a degree an
我在明尼苏达州的
undergraduate degree at Carlton College
卡尔顿学院获得了
in Minnesota in biology so I always have
生物学学士学位。我一直
loved science and biology understanding
热爱科学和生物学，喜欢了解
how things work and uh then for years I
事物是如何运作的。之后，我
worked as a laboratory research
做了多年的实验室研究
assistant different types of research
助理，在世界各地不同的研究
labs around the world Boston Munich
实验室工作，包括波士顿和慕尼黑，也从事过
including in diabetes research until
糖尿病研究。直到
I figured out what I wanted to do and I
我找到了自己想做的事情，我
decided that I wanted to go to medical
决定去
school so then four years of medical
医学院。于是，我在
Burlington Vermont which is a great
佛蒙特州伯灵顿的佛蒙特大学医学院读了四年，这是一所很棒的医学院。
and then so that was 25 years ago that I
之后，我在马萨诸塞州剑桥的哈佛大学附属医院完成了四年的精神科住院医师培训。25年前，我
finished my Psychiatry residency
完成了精神科住院医师
training and I've been practicing uh
培训，之后一直从事
Psychiatry ense and what does practicing
精神科工作。精神科的临床实践
involve what it usually involves for
通常包括哪些内容？
most psychiatrists is psychotherapy and
大多数精神科医生采用心理治疗和
medications and for some psychiatrists
药物治疗，有些精神科医生
only medications some psychiatrists
只用药物治疗，有些精神科医生则更
prefer to focus exclusively on
倾向于专注于
psychopharmacology or medication
精神药理学或药物
management there are some psychiatrists
管理，还有一些精神科医生
who choose to focus only on
选择只专注于
psychotherapy and and and don't
心理治疗而不
prescribe medications but the vast
开药，但
majority of psychiatrists offer a
绝大多数精神科医生都提供
combination of both medications and
药物治疗和
Psychotherapy and when did nutrition
心理治疗相结合的方案。那么，营养学是什么时候
become part of your career well I I
成为您职业生涯的一部分的呢？嗯，我
between food and the Brain once um
以前从未想过食物和大脑之间的关系。
lectures in four years and in four years
在医学院四年里，我们可能只上了两三个小时的营养学课，而在
of Psychiatry residency we didn't talk
精神科住院医师的四年里，我们一次也没有谈到
about food in the brain once so I
食物对大脑的影响。所以，说实话，我完全
honestly had no idea how important it
不知道它对
was to to brain health uh so I practiced
大脑健康有多么重要。所以，
conventionally as I was saying you know
正如我刚才所说，在我执业的前十年里，我一直采用传统的治疗方法，即
medications and Psychotherapy for the
药物治疗和心理治疗。尽管
much as I loved my work I it was
我热爱我的工作，但我
becoming painfully obvious that most
越来越痛苦地意识到，我的大多数
people in my practice were just not
病人病情并没有好转多少，
getting that much better like no matter
无论我
how hard I tried um and and it wasn't
多么努力。这不仅仅是
just true for me you know it wasn't as
事实。 对我来说，
though I was thinking well you know I
我
don't have an maybe I don't have enough
并不是在想，我可能
experience or maybe I not reading enough
经验不足，或者阅读不够，
or maybe I need more supervision um when
或者需要更多指导，
am I going to be able to really be able
我什么时候才能真正
to help people because when I looked
帮助到别人。因为我环顾四周，即使是那些从业几十年的
around even very senior psychiatrists
资深精神科医生，他们也面临着
same was true for them I mean we had
同样的问题。
we've been taught to think of mental
我们一直被教导要把精神
illnesses as chronic mysterious and
疾病看作是慢性、神秘且
incurable and that the best way you can
无法治愈的疾病，
help people is to support them with
帮助患者的最佳方法是用
medications and
药物和
Psychotherapy and uh but but that these
心理治疗来支持他们。然而，这些
are lifelong illnesses that we really
疾病是终身的，
don't understand very well and that we
我们对其了解甚少，也
can do very little about because you
几乎无能为力，因为
component to mental illnesses as well
精神疾病也包含着重要的社会因素。没错，
right absolutely I mean the brain the
大脑
brain is a very responsive organ and
是一个非常敏感的器官，
it's listening to uh it's not just
它不仅
paying attention to the food you eat
关注你吃的食物，还
it's paying attention to every aspect of
关注
your life how much light the brain
你生活的方方面面：大脑
receives how much love you have in your
接收到的光照量、你生活中拥有的爱、
life how how much you love your work
你对工作的热爱程度，以及你
what kinds of people are around you um
周围的人。 你
how you use your body exercise stress um
如何运用身体、运动、压力等等，所有这些都
everything everything matters to the
对大脑至关重要。
brain but most people are led to believe
但大多数人被误导，认为
that food doesn't matter that much to
食物对大脑并不那么重要。
the brain and that's partly because
这部分是因为
we've only recently started to think
我们最近才开始关注这个问题，
about it but the other piece um is that
但另一部分原因是，
the information that we're given about
我们被告知的关于
how to feed the brain and the body
如何正确滋养大脑和身体的信息
properly is incorrect and so when people
是错误的。因此，当人们
are trying their best to improve their
尽力
mental health using nutritional
通过营养策略来改善心理健康时，
strategies those strategies fail most
这些策略对大多数人来说都失败了，
people because those strategies are
因为这些策略是
grounded in the wrong information and so
基于错误的信息。所以
a lot of people just think oh well you
很多人会想：“哦，
know I I tried eating more Whole Foods
我尝试多吃天然食物，
or right I tried uh you know I tried
或者，我尝试在
putting blueberries on my oatmeal or
燕麦粥里加蓝莓，或者
making my flax seed smoothie every
每天早上做亚麻籽奶昔，或者
morning or uh eating more plants than
多吃植物性食物而不是
animals I tried all of those things and
动物性食物，我尝试了所有这些方法，但
they just didn't help very much so I'm
它们都没有什么帮助，所以我还是会回到以前那种
moderation um because it doesn't seem to
适量饮食的状态，因为看起来好像没什么
matter but what's really great about you
区别。” 但你
inviting me here to talk with you today
今天邀请我来这里和你交流，这真的很好，因为
is that people need to know how powerful
人们需要了解
and intervention uh these nutrition
营养干预的力量。
strategies can be they can help you in
策略可以
ways no medicine can in days to weeks in
在几天到几周内以药物无法做到的方式帮助你。在
many cases people can experience
许多情况下，如果人们掌握了
have the right information about how to
关于如何
change their diet so you have to know
改变饮食的正确信息，他们的情绪、记忆力、注意力、耐力、生产力、心理稳定性以及生活效率都会得到显著改善。所以你必须知道
which changes are the ones that are
哪些改变是
worth making and they're not the ones
值得做的，而这些改变并非
we're used to hearing about is there a
我们通常听到的那些。说到
when you think about this is there a
这，你脑海中会浮现出哪个具体的案例研究？有没有哪个
most prominent case study or a first
案例研究最为突出，或者说是让你灵光一闪的第一个
case study that was a Eureka moment
案例？
VI I wouldn't say there was a Eureka
我不会说
moment case in my life because I came to
我的人生中有什么灵光一闪的案例，因为我接触到这个领域的
it a in a different way uh my Eureka
方式不同。我的灵光
moment really came through my own
一闪实际上来自于我自己的
personal experience I think a lot of
个人经历。我认为很多
Physicians who uh practice nutritional
从事营养
and metabolic
和代谢
strategies most of us stumble into this
策略的医生，我们大多数人都是偶然进入这个领域的，
work accidentally because we're not
因为我们没有接受过这方面的
taught it and most of us stumble into it
培训，或者是
either because a patient comes to us and
因为病人来找我们
says hey you know I've tried this new
说：“嘿，你知道吗，我尝试了一种新的
way of eating and that's why I'm so much
饮食方式，这就是为什么我感觉这么好。”
healthier than when you saw me a year
比一年前你见到我时更健康，
ago or the The Physician themselves
或者说，医生自己也会
encounters their own health challenges
遇到健康挑战，
you know uses the conventional nutrition
你知道，他们采用传统的营养
approaches they don't help and they find
方法，但这些方法并没有帮助，他们发现
that they're kind of left to their own
自己只能靠自己
devices to solve their own health
解决健康
problems and that's exactly what
问题，而这正是
happened to me so when I was
我遇到的情况。所以，
of uh health issues in my early 40s
在我40岁出头的时候，
despite doing everything correctly you
尽管我做了很多正确的事情，比如
know eating uh low fat low cholesterol
低脂、低胆固醇、
calorie restricted diet um uh that was
限制卡路里的饮食，
high in fiber uh mostly Whole Foods and
高纤维，主要吃天然食物，并且
exercising religiously despite doing all
坚持锻炼，但
of those things my health was declining
我的健康状况
in my early 40s in ways that was true
在40岁出头就开始恶化，
for a lot of my patients as well and I
我的很多病人也是如此。我
had no idea how to help my patients with
不知道该如何帮助我的病人解决
these issues these were things like
这些问题，比如
chronic fatigue and IBS and fibromyalgia
慢性疲劳、肠易激综合征、纤维肌痛
and migrain headaches very common in
和偏头痛，这些在
middle-aged people and older and even
中老年人甚至
younger people nowadays so
现在的年轻人中都很常见。
when I encountered those issues and I
当我遇到这些问题时，我当时在
was working at Harvard at the time I had
哈佛大学工作，我可以
access to all kinds of Specialists
接触到各种各样的专家，他们既关心病人，又
caring intelligent thorough they did all
聪明，而且做事认真负责，他们做了
kinds of tests all kinds of tests and
各种各样的检查。 检查结果
they said everything is normal there's
显示一切正常，
nothing wrong of course there was
没有任何问题。当然，肯定是有
something wrong
问题的，
but I I so I instinctively
但我本能地
started experimenting with my
开始尝试调整
diet uh and long story short short 6
饮食。简而言之，经过
months later trial and error changes
六个月的反复试验，我调整了
food and symptom Journal at the end of 6
饮食，并记录了
months and this was back in
六个月后的症状变化。这发生在
2007 um the diet that I ended up on
2007年。最终，我通过反复试验找到的饮食方案
Purely by trial and error was almost
几乎与
we're told as healthy for us and that
我们通常被告知的健康饮食截然相反。正是这种
was the diet that resolved every single
饮食方案解决了
one of my physical health
我的所有身体健康
symptoms but as a psychiatrist what
问题。但作为一名精神科医生，
really got my attention was that it
真正让我注意到的是，它显著
improved my mental health significantly
改善了我的心理健康。
and I wasn't even trying I wasn't even
而我之前甚至没有
aware that my mental health needed that
意识到我的心理健康需要如此重视。
much attention I think like most people
我想，和大多数人一样，
I was walking around with suboptimal
我的
mental health you know more anxiety than
心理健康状况一直不太好，焦虑程度远超
was necessary than was I you know I
必要。我经常
slumping in the middle of the day brain
在中午感到精神萎靡，
hours after lunch coming home at the end
午饭后几个小时就开始昏昏欲睡，一天结束回家后更是
spent and not being able to get anything
筋疲力尽，
else done after 5:00 being really
五点以后就什么都做不了了。
anxious on Sunday night before Monday
周日晚上焦虑不安，周一
morning work um you know being depressed
早上还要上班，你知道，冬天抑郁也是常有的事。
things we think of as really normal
我们觉得这些都是很正常的事情，我们对
we've come to expect so little of our
自己的心理健康期望太低了，甚至把
mental health as normal and it
心理健康状况不佳当成了常态。但事实并非如此。
isn't uh if you feed the brain properly
如果你给大脑提供正确的营养，
it works better and you can expect so
它就能更好地运作，你也能对
much more of yourself so when that
自己有更高的期望。所以，当这些事情
happened to me I thought well that's
发生在我身上时，我想，这很
interesting this diet seems to be good
有意思，这种饮食似乎
for the brain which diet was that this
对大脑有益。这种饮食主要以
meat low carbohydrate low fiber low
肉类为主，低碳水化合物、低纤维、低
cholesterol high fat diet no whole
胆固醇、高脂肪，不含全
grains no
谷物和
legumes very few plant Foods mostly
豆类，植物性食物很少，主要是
Seafood meat poultry non-starchy
海鲜、肉类、家禽、非淀粉类
vegetables and fats from Whole Foods it
蔬菜，以及来自全食超市的脂肪。就这么
really was as simple as that and a Diet
简单。
similar to that is um uh one of the
类似的饮食是这
starting places in the book so I have a
本书的入门方法之一。我在书中提供了
variety of different dietary strategies
各种不同的饮食策略供
people can explore in the book not just
读者探索，而不仅仅是
one so it's different places for people
一种。所以，人们可以
to grab on depending on what they feel
根据自己的
comfortable doing but that but that way
舒适度选择不同的方法。这种
of eating resolved all of my physical
饮食方式解决了我的所有身体
issues and mental health issues I wasn't
和心理健康问题，而我之前甚至都没有
even aware needed attention
意识到这些问题需要关注。这才是
really was what inspired me to begin
真正的关键所在。 这激发了我开始
studying nutrition I certainly did not
学习营养学。我当然不会贸然
pattern to my patients that would have
向我的病人推荐这种饮食模式，那太鲁莽了。
been Reckless I didn't know the first
我
thing about nutrition and based on the
对营养学一窍不通，而且根据
little that I did know the diet that I
我当时仅有的那点知识，我
had ended up on should theoretically
最终采用的这种饮食方式理论上应该会要了
kill me so it could be dangerous for
我的命，所以它对
people and so I studied for years
其他人来说也可能很危险。因此，我自学了多年，
independently took a graduate course at
在哈佛公共卫生学院攻读研究生课程，
studied independently read everything I
阅读所有能找到的资料，
get my hands on studied the the primary
研究原始
literature the actual scientific studies
文献和实际的科学研究，
to try to understand okay why why is red
试图理解：为什么
meat bad for us what's the difference
红肉对我们有害？
between red meat and white meat why are
红肉和白肉有什么区别？为什么
whole grains good for us why are whole
全谷物对我们有益？为什么全
grains good for us but refined grains
谷物对我们有益而精制谷物
are bad for us why do we need a rainbow
对我们有害？为什么我们需要各种颜色的
of fruits and
水果和
vegetables uh are some of them more
蔬菜？它们之间是否存在一些
important than others are they all
比其他更重要的因素？它们是否都
equally beneficial I mean all I just
同样有益？总之，我对
became so curious about food I really
食物产生了浓厚的兴趣，我真的
wanted to get to the bottom of it so for
想弄明白其中的奥秘。所以，
years I studied nutrition and fell in
我花了数年时间学习营养学，并
love with nutrition science and um it's
爱上了营养科学。
a lot of what I share in the book is all
我在书中分享的很多内容都是
these fascinating things about food that
关于食物的奇妙知识，而这些知识
most people don't know um and that can
大多数人并不了解，而且它们真的非常重要。
really such as that it's interesting
比如，这很有趣，很有
it's useful it's empowering because if
用，也很有启发性。因为如果
you understand which foods contain the
你了解哪些食物含有
nutrients the brain needs which foods
大脑所需的营养，哪些食物
contain the ingredients that damage the
含有损害
brain which foods are going to damage
大脑的成分，哪些食物会损害
brain metabolism and cause inflammation
大脑代谢，导致炎症
and cause oxidative stress cause all
和氧化应激，以及所有这些
these things that we're told we need to
我们被告知需要
with supplements and
用补充剂和
superfoods um that's the real power the
超级食物来对抗的问题，那么真正的力量就在于此。
real power in dietary change is not
饮食改变的真正力量不在于
adding special things to the diet it's
在饮食中添加特殊的东西，而在于
actually subtracting the things that are
减少那些
harming the brain and working against
损害大脑、阻碍
your best efforts it's it's it's just
你努力的因素。就像
like anything you know you don't make
任何事情一样，你知道，你不会通过
money by spending money you make money
花钱赚钱，而是
by by not spending money right so it
通过不花钱赚钱，对吧？所以，这
it's the power of subtraction what are
就是减法的力量。
you not doing um and that's really Step
你不做什么？这才是真正的第一步：
One is first Do no harm understand where
首先，不要造成伤害。了解
the harm is coming from in the diet
饮食中的危害来自哪里，
because it's not where you think it's
因为危害并非来自你想象的地方，它
coming from it's not coming from the red
并非来自
meat it's not coming from the
红肉，并非来自
cholesterol it's not coming from the
胆固醇，也并非来自
saturated fat so if you understand where
饱和脂肪。所以，如果你了解了
the damage is coming from then you can
损害的来源，你就能
turn things around very
迅速扭转局面。
quickly you used a word there you used
你刚才用了一个词，你用了“
the word explore um as it relates to
探索”这个词，它和
different diets that you've written
你在书中写到的各种饮食方法有关，
about in your book and that you know
而且你知道这些方法在
that are available online
网上也能找到。
I from what I understood there you're
我的理解是，你
not saying that one diet is the right
并不是说有一种饮食方法适合
diet for everybody you're saying that
所有人，而是说“
it's almost the word explore suggests
探索”这个词暗示着某种
sort of experimentation personal
实验，个人的
experimentation and what worked for you
实验，对你有效的方法
in that case might not necessarily work
可能
for someone else in a different
对其他人在不同的
situation is that accurate that's
情况下无效，是这样吗？
exactly right and you're bringing up a
完全正确。斯蒂芬，你提出了一个非常
really important Point Stephen which is
重要的观点，那就是
dietary knowledge so one is that there
饮食知识有两个层次。一是
that apply to all human beings these are
适用于所有人的基本营养原则，这些原则是
the rules the cells require these
细胞需要的
nutrients um and you must consume foods
营养物质，你必须食用能够
that provide those nutrients to those
为细胞提供这些营养物质的食物，
cells and you must exclude these certain
并且必须避免食用某些
ingredients that can damage those cells
会损害细胞的成分，
and you must keep your glucose and
你必须将血糖和
insulin levels in in the right range for
胰岛素水平保持在适合
your personal metabolism you have to you
你个人新陈代谢的范围内。你
have to nourish protect and energize
必须滋养、保护和补充能量，
yourselves you must do that but then
你必须做到这些。但是
beyond that so so those rules and and
除此之外，还有一些其他的东西。这些原则，以及
the rules that you have to follow to to
你必须遵循的原则，并非人人都
known but then beyond that there's the
知道。
personalization right because we are all
个性化就在这里，因为我们每个人都
different we're not different in what
不同。
our cells need but we're different in
我们细胞的需求可能相同，但我们对食物的
what we can tolerate we're different in
耐受程度不同，代谢健康状况不同，
in how old we are how active we are what
年龄、活跃程度、现有疾病、高危疾病、目标、偏好以及
are what and and whether we have food
食物
sensitivities for example um and so all
过敏等都各不相同。所有这些因素，例如
you know food intolerances and and
食物不耐受、不同的
different different goals and different
目标以及
aspects of our of Our Lives that's where
我们生活的不同方面，都决定了
the personalization comes in and I teach
个性化的重要性。我
people in the book how to take these
在书中教大家如何运用这些
fundamental principles so I teach them
基本原则。我告诉他们什么是基本原则，其实
which are very simple nutrition is not
很简单，营养并非
rocket science um and and then show them
高深莫测的科学。然后我会教他们
how to personalize it to their
如何根据自身的代谢、
metabolism to their preferences to their
偏好和
goals what are the fundamental
目标进行个性化调整。那么，什么是基本原则呢？
principles let's start there so the
让我们从这里开始。基本
fundamental principles are nourish
原则是：滋养、
protect
保护、
energize so nourish what does a brain
能量。那么，什么是滋养？
healthy diet look like and by brain
大脑健康饮食是什么样的？
healthy uh we are talking about what's
我们所说的大脑健康，是指
healthy for all cells because it
对所有细胞都有益的饮食，因为如果只
wouldn't make any sense to uh for the
针对大脑细胞，那就毫无意义了。
human body to require different diet for
人体每个器官都需要不同的饮食，
every organ you possess so a brain
因此，大脑
healthy diet is a diet that's healthy
健康饮食是指对
for every organ in the body so it's good
身体每个器官都有益的饮食，它对
for the brain it's good for the heart
大脑、心脏、
it's good for the liver Etc so what is a
肝脏等都有益。那么，什么是
brain healthy diet it needs to nourish
大脑健康饮食呢？它需要滋养、
protect and energize
保护和提供能量。
nourish it must contain and be able to
它必须包含并能够
safely deliver all essential nutrients
安全地将所有必需营养素输送
to your cells so you have to know where
到细胞。因此，你必须知道
those nutrients are you cannot and using
这些营养素在哪里。你不能仅仅遵循
Whole Food principles and not including
全食物原则，不摄入
supplements or specially fortified
补充剂或特殊强化的
processed foods you cannot meet that
加工食品，就无法达到这个
goal without including some animal Foods
目标。如果你的饮食中不包含一些动物性食物，
in your diet that's just the truth of
这就是
our
我们
biology
生物学的真相。
protect protect the brain from damaging
保护大脑免受有害
ingredients so what damages the brain
成分的侵害。那么，什么会损害大脑呢？炎症，
inflammation which you can't see or feel
你既看不到也感觉
it's not as so the brain is red or
不到。大脑不会发红、
swollen or sore you we the brain doesn't
肿胀或疼痛。我们知道，大脑没有
have nerve endings but many many people
神经末梢，但很多人
have brain inflammation without being
患有脑炎症却不
aware of it that's a main driver of
自知。这是
depression and all kinds of other brain
抑郁症和其他各种脑部
conditions so you need to exclude
疾病的主要诱因。因此，你需要排除。
protection is not about addition it's
保护不是添加，而是
about subtraction you need to subtract
减少。你需要
the foods from your diet that cause
从饮食中减少那些会导致炎症的食物。 会
that caus something called oxidative
导致一种叫做氧化
stress which is why we're always told to
应激的现象，这就是为什么 我们总是被告知要
eat more
多吃
antioxidants what we really need to be
抗氧化剂，但我们真正需要
told is what's causing all that
知道的是，究竟是什么导致了所有这些
oxidative stress in the first place and
氧化应激，并
remove those things because the
消除这些因素，因为
antioxidant strategy really doesn't
抗氧化剂策略实际上并不
work and energize nourish protect
奏效。
energize the third principle is energize
第三个原则是“能量补充”，
which means the brain which is a very
这意味着大脑——一个
high energy electrical organ it needs a
高能量的电器官——需要持续
constant supply of high quality Quality
不断地供应高质量、
Clean burning energy and if you're
清洁的能量。如果你的
eating the wrong way your brain will not
饮食方式不正确，你的大脑将
will gradually lose its ability over
逐渐失去
time to generate energy that's primarily
产生能量的能力。这主要关乎将
about getting your glucose and insulin
你的血糖和胰岛素
levels into a healthy range not just
水平控制在健康的范围内。不仅仅是
your glucose although getting your
血糖，虽然将
glucose levels in a healthy range is
血糖水平控制在健康的范围内
extremely
极其
important you have to go one step
重要，但你还需要
further because underneath that glucose
更进一步，因为在血糖之下，
you need to know what's happening with
你需要了解
insulin and that's that's a really EMP
胰岛素的情况。这才是真正的能量补充
powering strategy sort of Next Level
策略，可以说是更高层次的策略。
insulin levels down will allow your
降低你的血糖和胰岛素水平将使你的
brain to uh uh to energize itself in the
大脑能够以
most clean efficient um and reliable way
最清洁、高效、可靠的方式自我补充能量，
possible nourish protect and
滋养、保护并
energize and then beyond there you said
补充能量。然后，正如你所说，还有
there's a level above there so that's
一个更高的层次，这就是
the sort of fundamental level Beyond
基础层次。 个性
personalization what's best for you and
化饮食的关键在于找到最适合你的方案，而这正是
is that where the sort of trial and
试
error comes into play exactly so these
错法发挥作用的地方。这些
principles nourish protect energize the
原则包括滋养、保护和赋能。滋养饮食
nourish you need to include some animal
需要摄入一些动物性
Foods the protect you need to exclude
食物；保护饮食需要避免
things like refined carbohydrates and
精制碳水化合物和
vegetable oils uh which are the
植物油等食物，这些都是
signature ingredients of the standard
标准
American diet or standard Western diet
美式饮食或标准西式饮食的标志性成分；
um and the the energize is is the the
赋能饮食则与
glucose and insulin levels which for
血糖和胰岛素水平有关。对
some people this is some a level of
某些人来说，
personalization begins here at the
个性化饮食的起点就在于赋
energized piece because if you have
能这部分。如果你代谢
excellent metabolic health and we can
健康（我们可以详细
talk about what that means then you may
讨论代谢健康的含义），那么你可能
not need to eat a ketogenic diet to to
不需要生酮饮食就能
glucose and insulin levels under control
有效控制血糖和胰岛素水平，
and thoroughly energize your brain cells
并为大脑细胞提供充足的能量。
but if you have significant metabolic
但如果你存在严重的代谢
damage if you're sedentary if you're
损伤，例如久坐不动、年龄较大、
older if you have pre-diabetes or type 2
患有糖尿病前期或2型
diabetes um then you may need to reduce
糖尿病，那么你可能需要减少
the amount of carbohydrate in your diet
饮食中的碳水化合物摄入量，
even from Whole Foods you may even need
即使是来自天然食物的碳水化合物也需要减少，甚至可能需要
to go to a ketogenic level and and
采用生酮饮食。
that's where that's where assessing your
因此，评估你的
metabolic Health understanding where you
代谢健康状况，了解你的
stand on the insulin resistant Spectrum
胰岛素水平至关重要。 胰岛素抵抗谱系，也就是代谢
the spectrum of metabolic Health that's
健康的谱系，是
the empowering piece because if you know
至关重要的。因为如果你了解
where you stand on the insulin
自己在胰岛素
resistance spectrum and you can get your
抵抗谱系中的位置，并且能够将
glucose and insulin levels into a
血糖和胰岛素水平控制在
healthy
健康
range you then you have tremendous power
范围内，那么你就能极大地掌控
over your emotional intellectual and
自己的情绪、智力
your and your physical health future
和身体健康。胰岛素抵抗
for almost all chronic diseases mental
几乎是所有慢性疾病（包括精神
and physical so personalization starts
和身体疾病）的首要风险因素。
with a metabolic personalization so how
因此，个性化治疗始于代谢个性化。例如，
much carbohydrate can you safely
你能安全耐受多少碳水化合物？这只是
tolerate that's one example but then
一个例子。但
there's another level of personalization
还有另一个层面的个性化治疗，它
that has to do with how well does your
与你的
immune system work how how good is how
免疫系统功能、
how robust is your gut function your gut
肠道功能和肠道
barrier many of us have lost our ability
屏障的强健程度有关。我们中的许多人已经失去了
to safely and comfortably tolerate a
安全舒适地耐受
wide variety of foods that we should be
各种原本应该
able to tolerate and that's because our
耐受的食物的能力。这是因为我们的
environment
环境
multiple multiple toxins in the
中存在多种毒素，它们
environment are have broken down a lot
破坏了
of our defenses our gut barrier bloodb
我们的许多防御机制，例如肠道屏障、
brain barrier uh and and our immune
血脑屏障，而且我们的免疫
system has become overwhelmed by trying
系统也因试图
to process lots of toxic ingredients in
处理环境中大量的有毒成分而不堪重负。
our environment so these are things like
这些有毒成分包括
Plastics and pesticides and antibiotics
塑料、杀虫剂、抗生素、
and um and and food additives and and
食品添加剂等等。
foods that we were never designed to
我们原本并不适应超加工食品，
handle these are really
这些食品
stressful on the human body and they do
对人体压力很大，而且会
break down our defenses over time so
随着时间的推移削弱我们的防御能力。因此，
this level of personalization is very
这种个性化的饮食方案
much about trial and error but to save
很大程度上依赖于反复试验。为了避免
people some of that frustration of trial
人们在反复试验中感到沮丧，
and error approaches I I give them very
我会提供非常
specific lists of foods
具体的食物清单，列出哪些食物
culprits than others and so that helps
比其他食物更容易导致问题。这有助于
cut back on some of the trial and error
减少试错过程。关于生
elimination this keto diet you um you
酮饮食，您
did a study on the ketogenic diet got
做过一项关于生酮饮食的研究，研究
the study here the ketogenic diet for
报告在这里：《生酮饮食治疗
refractory mental illness a resp a
难治性精神疾病：一项对
retrospective analysis of 31 in
31名患者的回顾性分析》。
patients what is the ketogenic diet for
对于可能不了解的人来说，什么是生酮饮食？
someone that might not know so a lot of
很多
people think or they've heard about a
人认为或听说过生
ketogenic diet as a weight loss diet um
酮饮食是一种减肥方法，
they think of it may maybe it's a fad
他们认为它可能是一种流行的
weight loss diet um they think of it as
减肥方法，他们认为它是
a very very low carbohydrate diet they
一种极低碳水化合物的饮食，或者
might think of it as a diet that's very
认为它是一种富含
high in meat and dairy products um and
肉类和乳制品的饮食。
but actually the ketogenic diet was
但实际上，生酮饮食
originally created in
最初是在
1921 more than a hundred years ago to
1921年提出的，距今已有一百多年历史。 为了
stabilize brain chemistry in children
稳定重度癫痫患儿的脑化学物质，在
long before the availability of useful
有效的
seizure medications so these were
抗癫痫药物问世之前，人们设计了生酮饮食。这些
children who um uh were having multiple
患儿大多
seizures per day in many cases and so
每天发作多次，因此，当时
then created back then a very strict
设计了一种非常严格的
version of the ketogenic diet um to get
生酮饮食，旨在
as close as possible to to fasting
尽可能接近禁食，同时
without Starving Children to death
避免让儿童挨饿致死。
because for
因为
Millennia people had noticed that those
几千年来，人们注意到
with epilepsy would often improve if
癫痫患者禁食后病情通常会有所改善，
they were fasting but you can't fast
但禁食是不可能的。
forever so how do you get close to
那么，如何才能接近
fasting this is the original fasting
禁食呢？这就是最初的
mimicking diet how do you get as close
模拟禁食饮食：如何在尽可能
to fasting as you can while still
接近禁食的同时，又能
providing some nutrition so that was the
提供一定的营养。这就是
original goal of the ketogenic diet and
生酮饮食的最初目标，它在治疗癫痫方面
was very successful for seizures more
非常成功，
than 50% of children had more than 50%
超过50%的儿童
and and adults as well it's it's since
和成人癫痫症状有所缓解。此后的研究
been shown more than 50% response rate
表明，
in children and and adults and 10 to 20%
儿童和成人的有效率超过50%，10%到20%的患者
completely uh free of seizures following
在接受生酮饮食后完全摆脱了癫痫发作。
ketogenic diet does many many things
生酮饮食对大脑的作用是什么？
it's like a multi-purpose tool for brain
它对大脑的影响非常广泛，就像一个多功能的脑
health so one thing it does because we
健康工具。我们之前
talked about how uh some of the root
讨论过，一些
causes of mental illnesses which are
精神疾病的根源，例如
research are inflammation and oxidative
炎症、氧化
stress and insulin resistance the
应激和胰岛素抵抗，是近年来才成为研究重点的。
ketogenic diet reduces inflammation it
生酮饮食可以减少炎症、氧化应激和
insulin resistance uh it also improves
胰岛素抵抗，还能改善
the balance of chemicals in the brain so
大脑中化学物质的平衡。
a lot of people think of um uh mental
很多人认为精神
illnesses as problems with chemical
疾病是
imbalances in the brain and these are
大脑化学物质失衡导致的，而这些
the chemicals that they're talking about
化学物质包括血清素、
dopamine or norepinephrine there are
多巴胺和去甲肾上腺素，还有
others glutamate Gaba many different
谷氨酸、GABA等等。
chemicals in the brain are uh associated
大脑中许多不同的化学物质都
with or in some cases even very much uh
与精神健康症状相关，甚至在某些情况下是
causing mental health symptoms but the
导致精神健康症状的主要原因。但
question is what's causing those
问题是，究竟是什么导致了这些
chemical imbalances in the first place
化学物质失衡？
inflammation and oxitive stress but
炎症和氧化应激是导致这些化学物质失衡的原因之一，而
another thing is that the brain is uh if
另一个原因是大脑本身……
you're feeding it the wrong way it will
你喂养的方式不对，
not be able to in many cases prod
很多情况下它就无法
produce energy reliably and if it can't
稳定地产生能量。如果
produce energy reliably all kinds of
能量无法稳定产生，
things will go wrong and in quite
就会出现各种各样的问题，而且会以非常
spectacular
严重的方式恶化。
fashion what actually goes wrong is
具体会出现什么问题
going to depend on who you are and
取决于你是谁，
that's where our individual differences
这就是个体差异所在。
come in so if I eat the if you and I
所以，即使你和我吃
exactly the same bad diet depending what
完全相同的糟糕饮食，根据
runs in your family and how you've lived
你的家族病史和你
your life to this point you might
迄今为止的生活方式，你可能会患上
develop Alzheimer's disease you might
阿尔茨海默病、
develop bipolar disorder you might
双相情感障碍、
develop type 2 diabetes you might
2型糖尿病、
develop fatty Li disease um I might
脂肪肝，或者其他
develop completely different conditions
完全不同的疾病，比如
cardiovascular disease I might develop
心血管疾病、抑郁症、注意力缺陷多动障碍（
depression um I might develop um ADHD it
ADHD）。这就是
and that's where the individual
个体
differences are but all of these
差异所在。但所有这些
conditions are just uh metabolic
疾病的根源都在于代谢功能
malfunction really at at the heart of it
紊乱。
that's what's going on if cells aren't
如果细胞
functioning properly you will develop a
功能异常，就会患上
disease physical and mental diseases and
疾病，包括生理疾病和心理疾病。至于具体患哪种疾病，很大程度上取决于运气。
luck of the draw um but you have
但
risk for if you understand how to help
如果你了解如何改善自身状况，就能极大地控制患病风险。
yourselves operate at their personal
你们都发挥出了
best can you tell me about what you
最佳水平，能否谈谈你们
learned in this study and what this
在这项研究中学到了什么，以及这项
study concluded yes so this was the work
研究得出了什么结论？好的，这项研究是
of my friend and colleague Dr Alber Dena
我的朋友和同事阿尔伯·德纳博士完成的。
he's a psychiatrist who's been
他是一位精神科医生，
practicing in tulo France for more than
在法国图洛行医超过
years so after witnessing a young family
年。他亲眼目睹一位患有
with autism and seizures improve within
自闭症和癫痫的年轻亲戚在
weeks of adopting a ketogenic diet he
采用生酮饮食几周后病情有所改善。于是他
thought well I wonder if this diet could
想，这种饮食是否也能
help my patients especially my patients
帮助他的病人，特别是那些对其他所有方法（包括
Psychotherapy medications
心理治疗、药物治疗和
hospitalization
住院治疗）都无效的病人。
and so he invited 31 of his most
因此，他邀请了31位病情最
treatment resistant patients with
难治的病人——患有
bipolar disorder major depression or
双相情感障碍、重度抑郁症或
schizophrenia to come into the hospital
精神分裂症——来到医院，在
hospital under his supervision to see
他的监督下自愿尝试一种非常温和的生酮全食饮食，看看
whether or not they would respond and
他们是否会有反应。这些
this was these were folks who these are
病人都是
all adults these were people who had
成年人，
been ill for an average of 10 years some
平均患病10年，有的甚至
for as long as 30 years these were
长达30年。
people who were taking when they came
他们来医院之前一直在服用药物。
the study an average of five psychiatric
研究开始时，入院患者平均服用五种精神类
medications not at all unusual for
药物，这对于
people with chronic mental illness and
慢性精神疾病患者来说并不罕见。
all of them had one or more markers of
所有患者都存在一种或多种代谢
poor metabolic health obesity high blood
健康不良的指标，例如肥胖、
pressure high blood sugar things like
高血压、高血糖等。
that so these were people with poor
这些患者代谢
metabolic health and poor Mental Health
健康差，精神健康状况也不佳。
heal and they eagerly came into the
他们渴望
hospital to try this intervention
尝试这种干预措施，
because nothing else had helped them and
因为其他方法都无效。研究人员
observed was that of the 31 people 28
观察到，31名患者中有28人
were able to stay on the ketogenic diet
能够坚持生酮饮食
for more than two weeks which is what
两周以上，这是
you need to do to start to see
开始看到
benefit every single one of them
疗效的必要时间。所有患者的病情都有所
improved to the point that 43% of them
改善，其中43%的患者
achieved clinical remission from their
达到了临床缓解，摆脱了难治性
psychiatric treatment resistant chronic
慢性
mental illness and 64% of them left the
精神疾病的困扰；64%的患者出院时
hospital unless psychiatric
无需服用精神类
medication and all of them improved
药物。所有患者的代谢状况也都有所改善。
not see results like this in
这种疗效在
conventional psychiatric care so there's
传统的精神科治疗中是看不到的。
you talk about the study the first is
谈到这项研究，有几点值得注意。首先，
that they were inside a hospital yes so
他们是在医院里接受治疗的。是的，
I guess that's a confounding Factor
我想这可能是一个混杂因素。
potentially oh yeah well a blessing and
嗯，有利也有
a curse yeah so a blessing is that um
弊。好处是，
the diet was fair was was very carefully
饮食方案很合理，而且受到非常严格的监督，一周七天中有
supervised six days out of seven they
六天他们都要严格执行，
were allowed to go home on Sundays okay
周日可以回家。
and which still I'm I'm just mentioning
我刚才只是提一下，
but that but they had tremendous amount
但他们得到了大量的
of support and supervision and and
支持和监督，这在
you're switching from a standard High
从标准的高
carbohydrate diet to a low carbohydrate
碳水化合物饮食过渡到低碳水化合物
diet they also had very careful medical
饮食时真的非常有帮助。他们还接受了非常细致的医疗
and psychiatric supervision which is
和精神科监督，这也非常
also really important uh because when
重要。因为当
you when you change to a ketogenic diet
你改用生酮饮食时，
brain chemistry fundamentally changes in
大脑的化学成分会发生根本性的变化。一
ways that can at first when you're
开始，当你
transitioning from one operating mode to
从一种运作模式过渡到
another operating mode it's it's
另一种运作模式时，会
stressful and sometimes you can feel
感到压力很大，有时你会
worse before you feel better MH and
感觉更糟，然后才会好转。心理健康和
medications can be affected so
药物治疗也会受到影响，所以
medications need to be monitored and
需要监测药物，一切都会发生变化。
everything everything changes these are
这些都是
all really healthy CH your blood sugar
非常健康的改变。你的血糖
can drop your blood pressure can drop
会下降，血压也会下降，
especially if you're taking blood sugar
尤其是在服用
lowering medications or blood pressure
降血糖药物或
lowering medications if you switch to a
降血压药物的情况下。如果你改用生酮饮食，
ketogenic diet it's so effective at
它在降低血糖方面非常有效。
lowering blood sugar many Physicians who
许多医生都认为生酮饮食对降低血糖非常有效。 给
medications for diabetes need to cut the
糖尿病患者开降血糖药物时，需要
diabetes medication in half on day one
在第一天将糖尿病药物的剂量减半，
in order to prevent dangerously low
以防止出现危险的低
blood sugar because you've got a
血糖。因为你已经服用了一种
medication that's lowering blood sugar
降低血糖的药物，
now you've added a diet that lowers
现在又增加了一种会降低
blood sugar and this could be
血糖的饮食，这可能存在潜在
potentially dangerous
危险。饮食
the diet on its own is not dangerous
本身并不危险，危险的
it's the diet in combination with
是饮食与
medications so you need to know what
药物的结合。所以你需要知道自己在做什么。是的，就这
these um 31 adults so a certain
31名成年人而言，其中一定
proportion of them was it 28 that
比例的人（
managed to see 28 31 283 had I just
28、31、28、3）能够观察到改善。如果我只是
restricted their calories for example
限制他们的卡路里摄入，
but kept them on whatever diet they were
而让他们继续之前的饮食，
on would I have seen an improvement as
是否也会看到改善？据
best of my knowledge however you're
我所知，还没有进行过类似的研究。不过，你
bringing up a really interesting point
提出了一个非常有趣的观点。
so what a ketogenic diet is it's really
那么，什么是生酮饮食？它实际上与
not about carbohydrate the definition of
碳水化合物无关。生
a ketogenic diet is any diet that lowers
酮饮食的定义是任何能将
insulin levels uh to the fat burning
胰岛素水平降低到脂肪燃烧
point so that if your insulin you can't
点的饮食。也就是说，如果
burn fat if your insulin levels are too
你的胰岛素水平过高，你就无法燃烧脂肪。
high and most people are walking around
而大多数人的
with insulin levels that are high 24
胰岛素水平都很高。
hours a day they don't even come down
一天几个小时，他们的血糖甚至不会在
overnight because people are just eating
夜间下降，因为人们吃得
too much too frequently in the wrong
太多、太频繁，而且吃的都是不健康的
foods to get into ketosis or generate
食物。要进入酮症状态或产生
ketones you need to lower your insulin
酮体，你需要将胰岛素
levels to the fat burning point and when
水平降低到脂肪燃烧点。当
you and if and if you're burning fat
你积极燃烧脂肪时，
vigorously the liver will turn some of
肝脏会将部分
that fat chop that fat into ketones
脂肪分解成酮体，酮体
which are very small fragments of ready
是脂肪的微小碎片，很容易被
to burn fat and these cross easily into
燃烧。这些酮体很容易进入
the into the brain and can be burned for
大脑，被燃烧产生
energy and they can Bridge any energy
能量，可以弥补
gaps that may be there which many of us
我们许多人可能存在的能量缺口。
have if these people had done the
如果这些人采用
Mediterranean diet would they have seen
地中海饮食，他们会看到
the same consequences the medit oh sorry
同样的效果吗？地中海饮食……哦，抱歉，
say I imagine they were probably on the
我想他们可能遵循的是
western diet that like the American diet
西方饮食，比如美国饮食，这种饮食
which is ultra processed high sugar so
高度加工且含糖量高。所以，
bringing them into a controlled
把他们带到一个受控的
environment and just depriving them of
环境中，剥夺他们摄入这些食物，肯定会产生同样的效果。仅仅是剥夺他们摄入这些食物，
on its own would have been beneficial
本身就很有益处。是的，
yes so I wrote in the paper I I I and I
我在论文中写道，我
I mentioned this you're making a really
提到了这一点。你提出了一个非常
excellent point and I addressed this in
好的观点，我在论文中也谈到了这一点。
the paper is that because when you when
因为当
you change from a standard junky modern
你从标准的垃圾现代
diet to through a ketogenic diet that's
饮食转变为生酮饮食（即
Whole Foods you're changing a lot of
全食物饮食）时…… 你改变了很多
variables right so how do we know that
变量，对吧？那么我们怎么知道
it had anything to do with the ketones
这和酮体有关呢？
right and and this is a good question
这是一个很好的问题，也是
and a fair question and we don't know
一个合理的问题。我们目前还不知道
the answer but new studies are helping
答案，但新的研究正在帮助
us to understand that but before we get
我们理解这一点。不过，在讨论这个问题之前，
to that I just wanted to say the point
我想说
you're making is so important because
你提出的观点非常重要，因为
there are lots of ways to lower your
有很多方法可以降低
insulin levels so you can lower your
胰岛素水平。
intermittent fasting you can lower your
你可以
insulin levels through exercise you can
通过禁食、间歇性禁食、运动或限制卡路里摄入来
lower your insulin levels through
降低胰岛素水平。
calorie restriction if you restrict your
如果你将
calories below 750 gram per day many
每日卡路里摄入量限制在750克以下，许多
people will go into ketosis that's
人会进入酮症状态。酮症是
another version of a fasting mimicking
另一种模拟禁食的
diet made Popular by Dr wter Longo so
饮食方式，由W.E. Longo医生推广。所以，
there are many ways to lower your
有很多方法可以降低
insulin levels um the ketogenic diet is
胰岛素水平，生酮饮食
just one way to do that but the
只是其中一种方法，但它
ketogenic diet is the only way to safely
是唯一能够安全、
sustainably maintain a state of ketosis
可持续地长期维持酮症状态的方法。
longterm ter so you can initiate you can
你可以
get into ketosis using these other
使用其他策略来进入酮症状态，
strategies but it's it you can't fast
但你不可能
forever you can't exercise all day long
永远禁食，也不可能整天运动，更
you can't restrict calories below 750
不可能限制卡路里摄入。 余生每日摄入量低于750卡路里，
for the rest of your life but you can
但你可以
safely and comfortably eat a a well
安全舒适地食用精心
formulated ketogenic diet which is very
设计的生酮饮食，这种饮食
low in carbohydrate moderate in protein
碳水化合物含量极低，
not excessive in protein and relatively
蛋白质适中（不宜过量），
higher in fat depending on your energy
脂肪含量相对较高，具体取决于你的能量
needs indefinitely sustainably use the
需求，并且可以无限期地持续食用。我一直以来
always been my challenge with the keto
在生酮
diet is being able to stay on it I mean
饮食方面遇到的挑战就是能否坚持下去。我的意思是，
you saw in this particular study that
你在这项研究中看到，
even trying to get people to do it for
即使只是让人们坚持
two weeks resulted in some portion of
两周，也会导致一部分
them dropping out yes um why is it so
人放弃。是的，为什么
hard to stay on the ketogenic diet I've
坚持生酮饮食这么难？我已经坚持了一段时间了。在
you before we started recording once a
我们开始录制之前，我跟你说过，每年这个时候
year around this time of year I do it
我都会坚持
for about eight weeks and it has a
大约八周，它对
really profound impact on a lot of my
我的​​生活产生了非常深远的影响。
life it helps me feel more focused um my
它帮助我感觉更加专注，我的
body composition radically changes
身体成分发生了巨大的变化，
faster than any other diet or thing that
比我尝试过的任何其他饮食或方法都快，甚至
I've ever tried faster than just
比单独运动更快。
better as well I
我还
noticed but you've been doing it for a
注意到我的睡眠质量也提高了一些。但是你已经坚持了很
long time you've been doing it for
长时间，
roughly almost 10 years for the better
差不多有十年了，而且大部分时间都在坚持。
part of TW I mean more often I'll say
TW，我的意思是，我更常说
I've been following a ketogenic diet for
我已经坚持生酮饮食
12 years and I agree with you it's not
12年了，我同意你的说法，这并不总是
always easy I'm not perfect about it
容易的，我自己也做得不够完美，
myself but I have been on the kog giant
但我过去
diet The Lion Share of the last 12 years
12年的大部分时间都在坚持生酮饮食。难是难点，是的，
because when you're trying to prescribe
因为当你试图把
it to somebody who is got you know
它推荐给那些患有
treatment resistant depression or is
难治性抑郁症或正在遭受其他
really suffering in some way I imagine
痛苦的人时，我想
they'll find it even harder than I do
他们会觉得比我更难。是的，
yes and no okay so uh it's well it's
也不完全是。好吧，嗯，毫无
definitely there's no question about it
疑问，
diet in a high carbohydrate world yeah
在一个高碳水化合物的世界里坚持低碳水化合物饮食是很难的。是的，除了
environmental Temptations and the social
环境诱惑、社交
Temptations and the habits and the
诱惑、习惯和
addiction sugar addiction is a very real
成瘾之外，还有糖瘾——糖瘾是一种非常真实的
biochemical phenomenon so there's that
生物化学现象。
but
但是，我的
but it I mean I've been I I had a weight
意思是，我从小就有体重
issue growing up everyone in my family
问题，我的家人也都有。我
different diets in my life this is the
一生中尝试过很多不同的饮食方法，这是最
easiest one to stay on I can't say about
容易坚持的，我无法评价其他任何
any other diet that I've follow for 12
饮食方法。 我坚持生酮
years and the reason why is this diet
饮食已经12年了，它之所以有效，是因为它能
really stabilizes appetite hormones
真正稳定食欲激素，让
so your cells are getting energized in
你的细胞在
between meals you're not getting those
两餐之间获得能量，避免
spikes and crashes in glucose which
血糖的剧烈波动。血糖波动会
cause spikes and crashes in appetite
导致食欲
hormones satiety hormones stress
激素、饱腹激素、压力
hormones reproductive hormones uh brain
激素、生殖激素以及大脑
chemistry um you're not getting you're
化学物质的剧烈波动。你不再经历这种
not on that roller coaster anymore so
过山车般的波动，
your cells are are are being satisfied
你的细胞
satisfied in between meals and
在两餐之间都能获得足够的能量，身体
inside it doesn't mean you're 100%
内部也变得平静祥和。但这并不意味着你就能百分百
protected against Temptation uh so I
抵御诱惑。我经常向
describe it to my patients with food
我的食物
addiction I describe being in ketosis as
成瘾患者解释，生酮状态就像
a suit of armor you know the sword can
一套盔甲，你知道，即使刀剑
still get you but you but you know
仍然能伤到你，但
you're not 100% protected but you've got
你拥有了
a real fighting chance and for for
真正的反击机会。对于
anybody who's never tried a ketogenic
那些从未尝试过生酮
diet and been on it for at least I would
饮食，并且至少坚持
say six to 12
6到12
weeks it most people have no idea how
周的人来说，他们可能根本无法想象
to follow a healthy eating plan when
坚持健康的饮食计划有多么容易。 当
their appetite is in good control a lot
食欲控制得很好时，很多
of people know they've shifted into
人甚至不用检查酮体仪就能知道自己已经进入
ketosis without even checking their
酮症状态，
Ketone meter because they can go for so
因为他们可以
long without eating without even
长时间不进食，甚至根本不会
thinking about food they can work
想到食物。他们甚至可以工作到
through lunch and not even realize that
午饭都吃不下，却浑然不觉
they've missed a
自己错过了一
meal most people the way we eat most of
顿饭。而我们现在的饮食方式，让我们大多数人无时无刻不在
us now are thinking about food all the
想着食物。
time you haven't even finished breakfast
你还没吃完早餐，就已经在
and you're already thinking what what
想
can I have for lunch you're carrying
午饭吃什么了。你走到
food around with you everywhere you go
哪儿都带着食物。
in many cases this is not the I mean we
在很多情况下，你一天至少要吃六顿饭。我的意思是，
if we needed to eat six times a day so
如果我们一天要吃六顿饭，我们这个物种根本无法生存下去。所以
we're not eating in a way that is that
我们现在的饮食方式既不能
is nourishing us and and satisfying us
滋养我们，也不能满足我们，反而
we're eating in a way that's making us
让我们更加
hungry I find what you've said there to
饥饿。我发现你说的有些道理，
especially in the context of the roller
尤其是在
coaster analogy so when I'm not on key
过山车的比喻中。所以，当我没有处于理想的
ketosis I do feel like sometimes I'm in
酮症状态时，我确实感觉自己有时就像坐
a bit of a roller coaster of like
过山车一样，一会儿被
Temptation craving Etc and then when I
诱惑，一会儿又渴望食物等等。而当我处于理想的酮症状态时，情况就完全不同了。
do ketosis and I get past the first week
酮症状态持续了一两周后，就像坐
or two the the roller coaster seems to
过山车一样，一切似乎都
stop right I'm I'm off the roller
停止了。我一下车，感觉就像从
coaster it's then maybe six eight weeks
过山车上下来了一样。但大约六到八周
later you're busy life happens you're
后，生活忙碌起来，
traveling you're tired that Temptation
旅行疲惫，诱惑就会悄悄
Creeps in and it just takes that one
袭来。只需要一瞬间的意志
moment of weakness in my head to then
薄弱，就能让
fling me off ketosis and all my effort
我脱离酮症状态，之前所有的努力都
is gone and in my head the way I've
付诸东流。而我的想法，就像我一直以来所认为的那样。 我仔细想过
this is wrong but I've thought about it
这个问题，我知道我的想法可能不对，但我一直在想，
like it takes a couple of days to get
进入酮症状态需要几天时间，
into a state of ketosis and then once
一旦进入酮症状态，
you're in and I usually get a headache
我通常会头疼。是的，
yeah on my way into ketosis I feel a
在进入酮症状态的过程中，我感觉
little little bit bad on the way in and
有点不舒服，但
then once I'm in there it's fine so when
一旦进入状态就没事了。所以，当
I have something that breaks my keto
我的酮症状态被打破时，
this is what I refer to me and my
我和我
girlfriend talk about I've broken my
女朋友就会说：“我的酮症状态又被打破了。”然后
keto whatever I think oh my god I've got
我会想：“天哪，我又得
to go through another headache and
头疼一次，还得再花
another five days of you know uh getting
五天时间才能重新进入酮症状态。”这是真的吗？
what is that correct it's a very common
这是一种很常见的
experience because there are these
经历，因为当
with your physiology uh as you're
你从
shifting from one operating system to
一种代谢系统切换到
another when you're shifting from
另一种时，你的生理机能会发生一些调整。当你从以
carbohydrate burning system to a more
碳水化合物为主的代谢系统切换到以脂肪为主的代谢
carbohydrate when you're shifting from a
系统时，你的燃料比例也会发生变化。身体和大脑就像混合动力引擎，所以我们永远不会只燃烧脂肪，而是燃烧脂肪和碳水化合物的混合物。 从
almost entirely by carbohydrate almost
几乎完全以碳水化合物为燃料的系统过渡
all the time to a system where you're
到以脂肪为主的代谢系统，这种
shifting back and forth
来回切换对某些人来说会很不舒服，
especially if what they have if if the
尤其是当他们
reason why you've quote broken your keto
打破生酮状态的原因
is because you've had something um that
是摄入了
has a lot of refined carbohydrate in a
大量精制碳水化合物，
lot of sugar or flour in it for example
例如糖或面粉时。
um so it depends on what you've eaten
所以，这取决于你吃了什么、吃了
and how much and for how long um but but
多少以及吃了多久。很多
many people do experience the so-called
人在
keto flu when they are shifting from a
从碳水化合物代谢系统过渡到脂肪代谢系统时都会经历所谓的“生酮流感”。其中
metabolism and some of this can be uh
一些症状
much of this can be prevented in a
可以通过
couple of different ways one is with
几种不同的方法来预防：一是
electrolyte supplementation
补充电解质，在
transitioning and another uh is by
过渡期间补充电解质以保持盐分平衡；二是
transitioning slowly onto the ketogenic
缓慢过渡到生酮
diet rather than all at once and so and
饮食，而不是一下子全部开始。
the book about how to do this more
书中还有很多其他关于如何更
comfortably but those are the two big
舒适地进行过渡的技巧，但以上两点最为重要：一是缓慢过渡。
ones uh and going slowly so in the book
因此，在书中，
I don't recommend that people start on a
我不建议人们一下子完全进入生酮状态。 直接开始生
ketogenic diet just straight away like
酮饮食，比如
learn about it on a Monday started on a
周一了解一下，
Tuesday but ease into ketosis over a
周二就开始，但要用一两周的时间慢慢进入酮症状态。
kind of a moderate carbohydrate plan in
书中有一个适度碳水化合物的方案，可以
the book that allows people to do this
帮助人们做到这一点。
so you you follow that plan for a couple
你可以按照这个方案坚持
of weeks to gradually lower those
几周，逐步降低
glucose and insulin levels it's going to
血糖和胰岛素水平，这样会
be a lot more comfortable it's be a lot
更舒服，
less of a shock to the brain and body um
对大脑和身体的冲击也会小得多。
and and if you're supplementing
如果你补充
electrolytes and going slowly most of
电解质并循序渐进，大多数
these quote keto flu symptoms will uh
所谓的“生酮流感”症状就
will not occur or they'll be very brief
不会出现，或者只会非常短暂
and Mild so um again these are posit
和轻微。所以，这些都是
it's a positive change to have these
积极的改变，补充
electrolyte changes and um it's it's all
电解质是有益的。所有
of these things are are good but there
这些都是好事，但确实
is this transition period which can
存在一个过渡期，
sometimes be uncomfortable and this is
有时会让人感到不适。这
um not to say that it's dangerous again
并不是说它很危险。
it's a very we're designed our biology
我们的生物机能让
is designed for us to be able to shift
我们能够在
back and forth between fat and
脂肪和
carbohydrate as fuel sources but many of
碳水化合物之间灵活切换作为能量来源，但
us have lost some of our metabolic
我们中的许多人已经失去了部分代谢
flexibility because we've done some
灵活性，因为……
eating the wrong way for too long so we
长期以来，错误的饮食方式损害了我们的新陈代谢，导致我们
don't shift as comfortably back and
无法像以前那样轻松地在各种状态间切换。
forth as we used to be able to I guess
我想
most people don't even know what foods
大多数人甚至不知道生
are included in a keto diet because most
酮饮食包含哪些食物，因为大多数
diets are restrictive to the point that
饮食限制都非常严格，以至于
you know people think they just make
人们认为它们只会让人痛苦
your life miserable but what are the
不堪。那么，
with the foods you're able to eat on a
关于生酮饮食可以吃的食物，你见过哪些常见的误解呢？
of a ketogenic diet is any way of eating
生酮饮食的定义是：任何能够
okay that lowers insulin levels enough
降低胰岛素水平，
to turn on fat burning and generate
从而启动脂肪燃烧并
ketones in the
在
blood because because it's about insulin
血液中产生酮体的饮食方式。因为它与胰岛素有关，所以
it the it's not a food list so you can
它不是一份食物清单。它与
you can it's not about plants and
植物和
animals it's not even about fat or
动物无关，甚至与脂肪或
carbohydrate it's about understanding
碳水化合物也无关，而是关于
how to lower your insulin levels which
如何降低胰岛素水平。
you can do with a vegan dietary pattern
你可以通过纯素饮食模式、
with a vegetarian dietary pattern uh
素食饮食模式、杂食
with an omnivore dietary pattern um uh
饮食模式，
with or even with a carnivore dietary
甚至是肉食饮食
pattern so whatever your dietary
模式来实现这一点。所以无论你的饮食
preferences are you can get the benefits
偏好如何，你都能从中受益。 生
the brain healing benefits of of ketosis
酮的疗愈功效，
so it's not about the foods you're
所以关键不在于你
eating um it's it's more about
吃什么，而在于
understanding what raises and lowers
了解哪些因素会升高或降低
insulin the things that raise and lower
胰岛素水平。会升高或降低
insulin are refined carbohydrates Whole
胰岛素水平的因素包括精制碳水化合物、全
Foods carbohydrates refined proteins
食物碳水化合物、精制蛋白质（
like protein powders whole food sources
如蛋白粉）和全食物
of protein and guess what barely touches
蛋白质来源。猜猜看，几乎不影响
insulin at all fat fat is metabolically
胰岛素的是什么？脂肪。脂肪是代谢上
the quietest and safest macronutrient
最稳定、最安全的宏量营养素，
you can eat because it barely stimulates
因为它几乎不刺激
insulin is ketosis a state like do I is
胰岛素。生酮是一种状态吗？
it like a binary State like now I'm in
它像一个二元状态吗？比如，我现在处于
ketosis and now I'm
生酮状态，现在又
not so yes but there's there's a yes um
不是？是的，但也有例外。
let me put it this way that most experts
大多数专家都
will agree
认同，
that um in order to be quote in
要达到所谓的“生酮状态”，需要测量
butter rate on a blood Ketone meter uh a
血液中β-羟基酮的水平。
blood Ketone meter U um is PR finger and
血液酮体检测仪（P 型）是一个手指，
and put a drop of blood on this little
滴一滴血在
test strip and it will read the amount
试纸上，它会读取
of a particular Ketone in the blood
血液中一种
called beta
叫做β-
hydroxate and it it will give you a
羟基酮的特定酮体的含量。
reading if that reading is point is 0.5
如果读数达到0.5
Millo or higher you are in ketosis in
mmol/L或更高，你就处于生酮状态。 酮症，
ketosis so what does that mean why why
那么酮症是什么意思？为什么
is the cut off 0 five because three
临界值是0.5？因为
things have to happen for you to get to
要达到
at least 0. five one is your glucose
至少0.5，必须满足三个条件：第一，血糖
levels have to come down the second
水平必须下降；第二，
thing is is your insulin levels have to
胰岛素水平必须
come down the third thing is you have to
下降；第三，必须
burn off a certain amount of the stored
燃烧掉肝脏中储存的一定量的
starch in your liver we have a a storage
淀粉。我们
tank for carbohydrate in our liver it's
的肝脏有一个碳水化合物储存库，但它容量
not very big it holds less than a day's
不大，只能储存不到一天
worth of carbohydrate because really as
所需的碳水化合物。因为作为
animals we're designed to store energy
动物，我们天生就倾向于以脂肪和碳水化合物的形式储存能量，以应对
Energy emergency short-term um the fat
紧急的短期能量需求。无论
we For Better or For Worse we have
好坏，我们
almost an unlimited capability to store
几乎拥有无限的脂肪储存能力，
fat we can store months and months and
可以储存数月甚至
months wor of fat and so um but we can
数月的脂肪。但是，我们
only store a very small amount of
只能储存非常少量的
carbohydrate so if your storage tank in
碳水化合物。所以，如果肝脏的储存库
the liver is full your body will not
满了，身体就不会
switch to fat burning because it says oh
切换到脂肪燃烧，因为它会说：“哦，
we've got plenty of starch to burn let's
我们有很多淀粉可以燃烧，那就先从淀粉
start there once it comes down to a
开始吧。”一旦血糖降到某个
certain point the body goes oh running
临界点，身体就会意识到“哦，
out of energy let's go to fat now and
能量不足了，现在该燃烧脂肪了”，
that's when the the liver will start
这时肝脏才会开始燃烧碳水化合物。
breaking fat down whether it's fat on
分解脂肪，无论是
your body or fat from your plate
你体内的脂肪还是餐盘里的脂肪，都会
and start chopping it up into these
将其转化为酮体。
ketones and uh but so those three things
这三件事
have to happen and once that happens
必须同时发生，一旦发生，
that you'll see the Ketone levels rise
你就会看到酮体水平
on the meter so most people who are not
在检测仪上上升。大多数不
eating a ketogenic diet are walking
进行生酮饮食的人，他们的
around with Ketone levels either
酮体水平要么检测
undetectable or they're 0 2 or they're
不到，要么在0.2或
three they might they might float up
3之间。
into above 05 every once in a while if
如果
they're not eating for a long time or um
他们长时间不进食，
uh or if they've just exercised but for
或者刚刚运动过，酮体水平可能会偶尔上升到0.5以上。但
the most part most people uh eating a
大多数
typical diet are not in ketosis and when
饮食习惯正常的人都不会进入酮症状态。当酮体水平
you get above 0.5 a lot of metabolic
超过0.5时，许多代谢
magic starts to happen because there are
过程就会开始发生，因为
lots of Pathways in the body and brain
身体和大脑中有很多通路
that uh are not very active unless
只有
you're in ketosis and those are the
在酮症状态下才会活跃。这些通路包括
healing Pathways the recycling and
修复通路、循环、
maintenance and cleanup Pathways the
维护和清理通路以及
recovery Pathways all of
恢复通路。
appreciate a number of years ago as I've
几年前，我在
been studying this is that
研究这个领域时逐渐意识到，
there are many people unfortunately or
不幸的是，很多人……
fortunately there are many people who
幸运的是，许多有
discover with mental health issues that
心理健康问题的人发现，
they need to be in ketosis long term in
他们需要长期保持酮症状态才能
well but I've become convinced by the
康复。但科学让我确信，
science that all of us need to be in
我们所有人都需要保持
ketosis um at least intermittently all
酮症状态，至少需要间歇性地
of us need to spend some time in ketosis
保持一段时间。我们都需要
on a regular basis or else we can't heal
定期处于酮症状态，否则我们就无法康复。这
we'll only be it it's like a it's like a
就像一个
manufacturing plant where the plant is
工厂，
just running 24/7 12 months a year and
一年365天，一天24小时不停运转，却从不
and they never take time to replace the
更换
parts or clean up the floor or you know
零件、清理地板，或者
they never do any maintenance work or
进行任何维护或
repair work and So eventually everything
维修工作。最终，一切都会
breaks down and when you say ketosis
崩溃。你说的酮症，指的
again you're not saying the the keto
不是生酮
diet you're saying the low levels of
饮食，而是指
glucose um and Insulin exactly in the
血液中葡萄糖和胰岛素的低水平。
blood and that can be achieved by
这可以通过
calorie restriction potentially fasting
限制卡路里摄入来实现，或许禁食也可以，
I guess you could achieve it and other
其他
diets like the Mediterranean diet if
饮食，比如地中海饮食，如果
administered in the right sort of doses
剂量合适，也能达到这种效果。
right well um we we should come back to
嗯，我们应该稍后再谈谈
the Mediterranean diet a minute but
地中海饮食，但
first the first part of your question is
首先，你问题的第一部分很
important because ketosis is you can as
重要，因为酮症…… 正如
you said you can get into ketosis a
你所说，
variety of different ways if you're
如果你
eating properly and this would have been
饮食得当，可以通过多种方式进入酮症状态。这或许是
our evolutionary Heritage our ancestors
我们的进化遗产，尤其是我们的祖先，
especially our prehistoric
特别是史前
ancestors um they have access to these
祖先。很久以前，他们能够接触到
lots and lots of refined carbohydrates a
大量的精制碳水化合物，但
long time ago um they were eating
他们主要食用的是
carbohydrates from uh Whole Foods uh
来自天然食物、
fruits and starchy root vegetables right
水果和淀粉类根茎蔬菜的碳水化合物。因此，即使是
and uh and so even grains and beans are
谷物和豆类，也相对来说是比较
very very relative relatively much newer
新的
sources of carbohydrate so let's think
碳水化合物来源。我们来想想
about fruits and vegetables but so they
水果和蔬菜，根据
look looking at their diets we don't
他们的饮食习惯，我们只能猜测。我们
have proof of this but think about it if
没有证据，但想想看，如果
you're eating in a way where your
你的饮食方式能够让你的
insulin levels are allowed to come down
胰岛素水平在
overnight if you're eating if you're
夜间下降，如果你
eating a a balanced diet so to speak but
吃的是均衡的饮食，包含你
it's got everything it needs in it and
所需的一切营养，
it's not giving you exaggerated spikes
不会导致
in your glucose and exaggerated spikes
血糖和
in your insulin and you're not eating
胰岛素水平的剧烈波动，而且你不会
six times a day or all day long your
一天吃六顿或全天进食，那么你的
insulin levels will naturally come down
胰岛素水平自然会在夜间下降，这将使
you to go into a healing mode so I
你能够…… 进入修复模式，所以我
believe that if people have the right
相信，如果人们掌握了
information about what a healthy diet is
健康饮食的正确信息，
supposed to look like they may may not
他们可能
even need to in many cases especially if
根本不需要节食。尤其是在
you're younger or athletic or don't have
年轻、运动能力强或代谢
a lot of metabolic damage already um you
损伤不严重的情况下，
may not need to you may not need to
你可能不需要
lower your carbohydrate intake during
减少白天的碳水化合物摄入量，只
the day you might just need to be
需要
careful about what kinds of carbohydrate
注意摄入的碳水化合物种类
you eat and how often um so for example
和频率即可。例如，
it's known that in children um they're
众所周知，儿童如果饮食
who are eating a regular diet many of
正常，很多孩子
them wake up the next morning in ketosis
第二天早上醒来就处于酮症状态，
they're metabolically much healthier
他们的代谢
than uh we are as we get older so
比我们成年人健康得多，代谢也
they're much more metabolically flexible
更灵活。即使他们
um and uh so now they didn't go on a
没有
ketogenic diet they were eating a
进行生酮饮食，只是
regular diet they slept overnight didn't
正常饮食，晚上睡觉没吃
eat anything the next morning they're in
东西，第二天早上也处于
ketosis that's not true for all children
酮症状态。虽然并非所有儿童都如此，
but it's true for enough children that
但对于足够多的儿童来说，这种情况
we know it's possible most adults it
是可能的。大多数成年人
into ketosis even if they're not eating
即使完全不进食，也至少需要几天时间才能进入酮症状态。
anything at all so f fasting can take 2
所以，禁食可能……
to 3 days at a minimum for most people
大多数人至少需要2到3天才能
to get into ketosis but some people it
进入酮症状态，但有些人
can take a whole week and you talked
可能需要整整一周。你刚才提到了
about children there one of the big
儿童，
conversations at the moment around
目前关于
children is the the rise in ADHD
儿童的热门话题之一是多动症
diagnosis and there's a lot of different
诊断率的上升。关于其成因以及导致儿童神经发育障碍诊断率不断上升的原因，有很多不同的
sort of thoughts on the causal factors
看法。是否
disorders is there any evidence to
有证据
suggest that what we're eating is
表明我们的饮食
playing a role in these neurod Divergent
在这些神经发育障碍中起作用？
yes the first thing I would like to tell
是的，我想告诉你的第一点
you about is that there were studies
是，在
quite a few studies back in in 80s 90s
20世纪80年代、90年代
and early 2000s in Europe by variety of
和21世纪初，欧洲有很多
different research teams that explored
不同的研究团队进行过一些研究，探讨了
exactly the question you're asking and
你提出的这个问题。他们的
what they did um was they placed
做法是，让患有
children with ADHD some quite severe
多动症的儿童（其中一些病情相当严重，
ADHD even Hospital level ADHD
甚至需要住院治疗）进行
and put them on something called a few
一种叫做“少食多餐”的
Foods diet this is uh the scientists
饮食。科学家
call it an oligo antigenic diet which
称之为低过敏原饮食，
just means it's kind of a low allergen
也就是说它是一种低过敏原
diet so it's they removed all of the
饮食。 他们剔除了所有
common culprits and they focus mostly on
常见的罪魁祸首，主要专注于
just a few Whole Foods uh and and and a
几种天然食物，以及
few extras so very specifically
一些额外的食物。具体来说，
describing this diet most of these diets
这些饮食方案大多包含
were um chicken lamb fruits vegetables
鸡肉、羊肉、水果和蔬菜。
um and sometimes they throw in some
有时他们会加入一些苹果
apple juice and margarine because they
汁和人造黄油，
couldn't use butter because Dairy is a
因为乳制品是常见的过敏原，所以不能使用黄油。
common allergen so but these were mostly
但这些
Whole Foods diets you know uh uh poultry
饮食方案主要以天然食物为主，包括家禽、
red meat fruits vegetables um and there
红肉、水果和蔬菜。
no matter which study you looked at and
无论你查看哪项研究，这些饮食方案的有效率都在62%到82%之间。
in some of these studies there was a 70%
在一些研究中，将
cure rate within weeks of changing the
饮食改为几种食物后，几周内的治愈率达到了70%。
this tell us
这告诉我们什么呢？这并
it doesn't tell us which foods were the
没有告诉我们哪些食物是
problem it tells us that food can be the
问题所在，而是告诉我们食物可能是
problem that if you make diet the right
问题所在。如果饮食方案调整得当，即使是患有
children even with very severe ADHD to
非常严重的注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD）的儿童，也可能在
improve within weeks to the point that
几周内得到改善，甚至
they no longer qualify for having ADHD
不再符合ADHD的诊断标准，
anymore because there's a change in the
因为他们的
symptoms oh yes um the children's uh
症状发生了改变，尤其是
Behavior as rated by parents and
行为方面。 根据家长、
teachers um and the researchers
老师和研究人员
themselves so just uh did some research
自身的评价，我做了一些研究，
to find some stats on this sure diet
找到了一些相关数据。饮食
modification isn't widely prescribed as
调整并没有被广泛用于
a way to alleviate ADHD symptoms is it
缓解多动症症状，对吧？
it says as of 2019 major health
截至2019年，
organizations including the American um
包括美国
Academy of Pediatrics and the National
儿科学会和英国国家
Institute of Health and Care Excellence
健康与临床优化研究所在内的主要健康组织
do not recommend dietary modifications
均不建议将饮食调整
as standard treatment for ADHD due to
作为多动症的标准治疗方法，因为
evidence a 2014 review found elimination
证据不足。2014年的一项综述发现，排除
diets might offer minor benefits in sub
饮食法可能对
in a subset of children particularly
部分儿童，特别是
those with food sensitivities or
那些对食物敏感或
allergies however these benefits are not
过敏的儿童，带来轻微的益处。然而，这些益处
substantial enough to advocate for
不足以支持
widespread dietary changes in ADHD
在多动症管理中广泛采用饮食改变。
management so what I would say to that
所以我想说的是，
is uh there are multiple studies all
有很多研究都
pointing in the same direction that I
指向同一个方向，我
think give parents and families and
认为这能给家长、家庭和
children tremendous hope with really no
孩子们带来巨大的希望，而且几乎没有任何
risk MH what are we doing
风险。我们现在在做什么呢？
instead we're medicating children we're
我们给孩子们服用药物，给他们服用
stimulants which can stunt their growth
兴奋剂，这会阻碍他们的生长发育，
make them anxious um and and cost money
让他们焦虑，而且还要花钱。我
reasons I do this work is
做这项工作的原因之一就是
because I really don't think that for
因为我真的…… 别以为对
most people the right thing to do is to
大多数人来说，用药物来摆脱困境才是正确的做法。我的
mean just about every mental and
意思是，
physical health issue we have is we
我们几乎所有的身心健康问题，似乎都习惯性地
condition to think about medications as
认为药物是
the solution but medications don't solve
解决之道。但药物并不能解决
problems they cover them up and what we
问题，它们只是掩盖问题。我们
really want to do is want to get to the
真正想要的是找到
root of these problems and not just
这些问题的根源，而不仅仅是
treat them which nutrition interventions
治疗它们。营养干预
can do in many
在很多情况下可以做到这一点，甚至可能从一开始就
cases but perhaps even prevent them from
预防它们的
happening in the first place can they
发生。所有这些问题都能通过药物
all be treated by because you know I I
治疗吗？你知道，我被
was I guess technically diagnosed with
诊断出患有注意力缺陷多动障碍（
ADHD but I don't take any medication for
ADHD），但我没有服用任何药物。这是我的
it I'm it's a personal choice I
个人选择。我
personally just um don't think that the
个人认为，服用任何药物
net impact has on my life is worth
对我的生活造成的负面影响都不值得。
taking any medication I also have
我也有一些患有
friends with ADHD who have significantly
ADHD的朋友，他们的
worse symptoms when I say worse I mean
症状比我严重得多——我说的严重是指
more pronounced symptoms than I do so my
症状更加明显。所以我
personal decision was just not to take
个人决定不服用
the medication however I sat here with a
药物。然而，我和一位
guy called Dr aan Who has a daughter who
名叫安医生的先生坐在一起，他有一个
had ADHD she got the medication and it
患有ADHD的女儿。她服用了药物，这彻底
turned her life around like she went on
改变了她的人生，她后来
to become super successful but was like
非常成功。 就像
struggling in school so
在学校里挣扎一样，
it's really difficult isn't it because
这真的很难，不是吗？因为
it's such a personalized sort of
这完全是
personal decision
个人选择，
and some people have it more extreme and
而且有些人的情况更严重，
in a way that makes their life more
在某种程度上，这让他们的生活
dysfunctional than others you know and
比其他人更加不正常。你知道，我的一些
my some some of my friends do really say
朋友确实会说，
they say I took this medication for my
他们服用这种药来治疗他们的注意力缺陷多动症（
ADHD or my my tension issues whatever
ADHD）或紧张问题等等，
and it's been revolutionary for me they
这对我来说简直是革命性的。他们会跟
just like they they just offload on me
我倾诉这种药
how profound it's been for them
对他们有多么深刻的影响。
so I guess it goes back to being a
所以我想，这最终还是取决于
personal it does but you
个人情况。不过，
know so I have a lot of experience
我在治疗ADHD方面有很多经验，
treating ADHD because I worked for two
因为我曾在波士顿郊外
years at an ADHD Specialty Clinic called
一家名为Hallowell Center的ADHD专科诊所工作了两年，还在
mental health at Harvard and at Smith
哈佛大学和史密斯学院的大学心理健康部门工作了13年，
college and saw lots and lots and lots
见过很多很多
of students with ADHD most of who
患有ADHD的学生，其中大多数
actually had it some of who didn't
确实患有ADHD，但也有一些没有，
who're just looking for stimulants but I
他们只是想找兴奋剂。但
I can tell you as a psychiatrist who's
我可以告诉你，作为一名从业
prescribed medications for 25 years the
25年的精神科医生，我可以开处方药，
stimulants are some of the most
兴奋剂是
effective medicines we have in our
我们工具箱里最有效的药物之一，对那些真正需要
toolbox for the people it works for it
它的人来说。 它
works very very well so and it can be
效果非常好，而且可以
life-changing a lot of people think of
改变人生。很多人认为
ADHD as oh a minor issue oh you can't
多动症只是个小问题，比如注意力不
concentrate or or maybe you're Daydream
集中、容易走神、坐立不安或者容易分心。但多动症
maybe you get distracted 8 HD can be a
可能是一种
really serious condition just like all
非常严重的疾病，就像所有
mental health conditions it exists on a
精神健康问题一样，它的严重程度也存在一个
spectrum of mild to very severe and so
谱系，从轻微到非常严重不等。
people with ADHD are at much higher risk
患有多动症的人更容易产生
for suicidal ideation they're much
自杀念头，更
higher risk for substance abuse they're
容易滥用药物，更容易发生意外，更容易患上抑郁症和
anxiety these and and twice the twice
焦虑症。此外，患有
adults with ADHD these are serious can
多动症的成年人离婚率是普通人的两倍。这些都是很严重的问题，
be for some people
对某些人来说，多动症甚至会严重影响他们的
cannot function in their lives they
日常生活。患者无法正常生活，无法处理
can't function in their relationships
人际关系，
they can't hold a job you know they they
无法维持工作。他们会
feel so frustrated and
感到非常沮丧和
Powerless I mean I was telling you that
无力。我之前说过，
I worked with students in in in you know
我曾在
these Elite universities right these are
一些精英大学里和学生一起工作，这些学生
very intelligent people who were
都很聪明，但他们在
peers in in classes they had to work so
课堂上付出的努力是同龄人的十倍，他们必须付出
much harder they had to stay up four or
更多努力。 他们
five hours later than everybody else and
比其他人晚睡四五个小时，
and and they did because they were
而且他们确实这么做了，因为他们很
hardworking but they're really suffering
努力，但他们真的很痛苦。
and this discrepancy
这种“
between how smart I am and how much I
我有多聪明，我
think I should be able to do and how
觉得自己应该能做到什么，而
much I'm actually able to do makes me
我实际能做到什么”之间的差距，让我感到很
feel bad about myself right they feel
沮丧，对吧？他们也对自己感到
bad about themselves and because they
沮丧，因为他们
know they're capable of more but they
知道自己有能力做得更多，但却
can't get there and it's a real
无法做到。这是一种真实的
biological condition now the great thing
生理疾病。
about this is a perfect example that you
这件事的妙处在于，它是一个完美的例子，
could we could have this conversation
我们可以就
about any mental health condition but
任何心理健康问题展开讨论，但
ADHD is a great example
多动症就是一个很好的例子，
because there's always a risk benefit
因为在
analysis when you're thinking about how
考虑如何
are we going to treat this condition uh
治疗这种疾病时，总是需要进行风险收益分析。
so do you want to take medication what
比如，你想服用药物吗？药物的
are the pros and cons of that does the
利弊是什么？
medication work for you does it give you
药物对你有效吗？它有
side effects can you access the
副作用吗？你能获得
medication uh can you afford the
药物吗？你能负担得起
medication um how hard is is lifestyle
药物吗？改变生活方式对你来说有多难？改变生活方式是
interventions for edhd and I think
治疗多动症最有效的干预措施之一，我认为
most Stellar examples I can think of is
我能想到的最棒的例子之一就是
this change your lifestyle to suit your
改变你的生活方式，发挥你的
strengths play to your strengths and
优势。 发挥你的优势，
don't try to swim upstream against your
不要试图逆流而上对抗你的
weaknesses people with ADHD often have
弱点。患有注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD）的人往往
tremendous talents in certain areas and
在某些领域拥有巨大的天赋，
are tremendously gifted in certain ways
在某些方面极具才能，
because they can make connections
因为他们善于建立联系，他们的
because they don't always think in a
思维方式并非总是
straight line because they they often
循规蹈矩，他们通常
have very diverse interests and they can
兴趣广泛，能够
pull different kinds of information
整合各种信息。
together and you know given the right
你知道，如果走对了
path they can be hugely successful right
路，他们就能取得巨大的成功，对吧？
but that's not possible for everybody
但这并非人人都能做到，
and for more severe cases of ADHD it's
对于更严重的ADHD患者来说，这根本
not possible at all has there been any
不可能。目前是否有关于
ketogenic diet and ADHD so not yet but
生酮饮食与ADHD之间联系的研究？还没有。但
I'm I'm very excited to to to be
我很兴奋能
involved in two brand new studies of the
参与两项关于
ketogenic diet for ADHD so one is a uh
生酮饮食治疗ADHD的全新研究。一项是针对患有
ketogenic diet for uh adults with ADHD
ADHD和抑郁症的成年人的生酮饮食研究，将于
2025 and the other is a study of uh
2025年在牛津大学启动；另一项是针对患有ADHD的成年人的生
ketogenic diets for ADHD and adults at
酮饮食研究，
the University of Michigan it's also
也将
going to be starting in 2025 we have no
在2025年在密歇根大学启动。我们目前还没有
data on ketogenic diets and ADHD but we
关于生酮饮食和ADHD的数据，但我们
have good reason to believe the reason
有充分的理由相信两者之间存在联系。
we were able to get funding for these
我们当时 之所以能够获得这些
studies is because there's there's
研究的资金，是因为
reason to believe that it could be
有理由相信它们可能
useful and because when you look at ADHD
有用，而且当你研究多动症时，
you see Clues to poor metabolic health
你会发现一些代谢健康不良的线索。
so for example children with obesity are
例如，肥胖儿童患多动症的
twice as likely to have ADHD obesity is
可能性是正常儿童的两倍，而肥胖是
a marker for insulin resistance adults
胰岛素抵抗的标志；
with type 2 diabetes are twice as likely
2型糖尿病成人患多动症的可能性也是正常成人的两倍，
to have ADHD type two diabetes is severe
2型糖尿病是严重的
endstage insulin resistance and the
终末期胰岛素抵抗，而
ketogenic diet is the most effective way
生酮饮食是我们目前所能利用的最有效的
to address insulin resistance that we
胰岛素抵抗治疗方法。那么，
establish cause and effect there
确定其中的因果关系是否困难呢？
I was thinking about the the diabetes
我一直在想，
one where if you've had ADHD maybe your
如果你患有多动症，你的
life has been harder again I don't know
生活可能更艰难。我不太确定
what I'm talking about here but maybe
我在这里说的到底是什么意思，但你的
life has been harder you're more likely
生活可能更艰难。如果你的生活更艰难，你更有可能
to be obese potentially if you've been
肥胖，比如
you've had a a worse a worse more
你承受了更大的压力，或者你从事着更糟糕、更具
challenging job and so is it you
挑战性的工作。那么，是否有
know and will will a test be able to
测试能够
exclude these sort of confounding
排除这些混杂
factors to the point that we'll know for
因素，从而让我们确切地知道答案呢？
difficult study to to design but I think
我认为这将是一项非常难以设计的研究。
what I can tell you from my clinical
根据我的临床工作经验，我可以告诉你，
work CU I work I'm a general
我是一名全科
psychiatrist so I see adults of all ages
精神科医生，所以我接诊各个年龄段的成年人，
and with all psychiatric conditions from
以及各种程度的精神疾病患者。正如
major to minor and I've worked as I said
我之前提到的，我接触过
hundreds and hundreds of patients with
成百上千的
ADHD what I can tell you is that it's
多动症患者。我可以告诉你，
the same with medication um if someone
药物治疗也是如此。如果有人
comes in and says to me uh I can't tell
来问我：“我感觉不到
if this medication is working um uh so
这种药有没有效果，我应该
should I keep taking it and I'll say
继续服用吗？”我会说：“
well you know if you can't feel it
如果你感觉不到它的
working then it's not working uh so when
作用，那就说明它没有效果。”
the diet works it works regardless of
饮食疗法有效时，无论周围环境如何，它都能发挥作用。
this is true for all conditions that
这一点适用于我接触过的所有疾病，包括双相情感障碍、抑郁症、多动症、创伤后应激障碍和
anxiety as you have said we talked about
焦虑症。正如你所说，我们讨论过生
the ketogenic diet is not easy to stick
酮饮食并不容易坚持，对吧？
to right people fall off the ketogenic
人们经常会中断生酮
diet all the time uh sometimes
饮食，有时是
accidentally sometimes intentionally
无意的，有时是故意的。
right and you can see their symptoms
你会发现，即使他们的外部环境没有改变，他们的症状也
come back within often 24 hours even
常常会在24小时内复发。 生活
though their external factors have not
因素没有
changed so life hasn't changed it's the
改变，所以生活方式也没有改变，关键在于
diet and when you follow the actual
饮食。当你
Ketone levels daily you can make that
每天监测酮体水平时，就能发现这种
correlation so what's really exciting
关联。这
about both of these studies is it's not
两项研究真正令人兴奋的地方在于，它们不仅仅是
just getting somebody into ketosis it's
让受试者进入酮症状态，而是
tracking um on a data to-day basis their
每天追踪他们的
Ketone level and their attention
酮体水平和注意力
symptoms and seeing if we can see them
症状，观察它们是否
go up and down together and we've always
同步波动。我们已经
get a little bit of data already from a
从牛津大学阿里·休斯顿（Ali Houston）的一项试点研究中获得了一些数据，
starting to see some signals there but
开始看到一些迹象，但现在下结论还
it's too early really uh we need to
为时过早，我们需要
actually launch the official study so in
正式启动这项研究。在
my
我的
patients it's it's a phenomenon I've
病人身上，这种现象我反复观察到。
um a great example is I have a
一个很好的例子是，我有一位
patient um that I worked with for a
病人，我曾与他共事
couple of years who had a a condition
几年，他患有一种
called bipolar disorder type two so it's
叫做二型双相情感障碍的疾病。这是
a it's a form of bipolar disorder uh
一种双相情感障碍，
bipolar disorder people used to call
人们过去常称之为
manic depression you've got periods of
躁郁症。这种疾病的特点是躁狂发作期之后
mania often followed by periods of deep
通常会紧接着一段抑郁发作期。
depression bipolar type 2 is a milder
双相情感障碍2型是一种较轻的
form where you don't get quite as manic
类型，躁狂症状不会那么严重，
um and but you still can can get very
但仍然会感到非常
depressed so he had bipolar to um and
抑郁。他患有双相情感障碍，所以
whenever so so uh he came to me because
他来找我，因为
he wanted to try a ketogenic diet for
他想尝试生酮饮食治疗
bipolar disorder because um uh uh he had
双相情感障碍，因为他
heard it might help so the other issue
听说生酮饮食可能有效。
he was dealing with was that he um and
他面临的另一个问题是，他和
his wife were having some difficulties
妻子的婚姻出现了一些问题，这些问题
that had started up a few years before
几年前就开始出现了。
and you know every time they got into an
你知道，每次他们吵架，
argument he would want to die and he
他都会想死，
would start to think about ways of
开始思考各种自杀的方法。
self every single time he went on the
每次他开始生
ketogenic diet the suicidal ideation
酮饮食后，自杀念头就会
went away even though his wife had not
消失，尽管他的妻子并没有。
so he used to associate the depression
他过去常常把抑郁症
with the marriage but he learned over
与婚姻联系起来，但随着时间的推移，他学会了将抑郁症
time to associate it with his metabolic
与他的代谢
state that when he was in ketosis he
状态联系起来。当他处于酮症状态时，他
could then imagine other ways of coping
可以想象出除了自杀之外的其他应对
with the stress in his marriage other
婚姻压力的方法。
of people say to me that the ketogenic
很多人告诉我，生酮
diet gives this space it allows them to
饮食能提供这样的空间，让他们能够
pull back and see things from a
退后一步，从
different perspective it buys them time
不同的角度看待问题。 从时间
perspective it's like a buffer so that
角度来看，这就像一个缓冲，让
people people aren't reacting as
人们在面对困境时不会像以往那样本能地做出反应。虽然困境本身并
situation hasn't changed but people are
没有改变，但人们
able to deal with the situation in a
能够以
more effective way they feel they have
更有效的方式应对。他们感到自己
more control not just over their
不仅对自己的
emotions but also over their behaviors
情绪，也对自己的行为
and how they react to situations
以及对各种情况的反应有了更多的掌控。
at my company flight Studio which is
在我的公司 Flight Studio（
part of my bigger company flight group
隶属于更大的公司 Flight Group）里，
we're constantly looking for ways to
我们一直在寻找
build deeper connections with our
与受众建立更深层次联系的方法，
audiences whether that's a new show a
无论是推出新节目、新
product or a project it's why I launched
产品还是新项目。这就是我推出
the conversation cards I've relied on
对话卡片的原因。我
Shopify before who's a sponsor of
之前就使用过 Shopify，他们也是
today's podcast and I'll be using them
今天播客的赞助商，而且我将在下一次
again for the next big launch which
重大发布中再次使用他们，
we'll hear about soon and I use them
我们很快就会听到相关消息。我使用 Shopify 的
because of how easy it is to set up an
原因是，它能让你轻松搭建一个
online store that reaches all of you no
在线商店，触达世界各地的所有人。有了
Shopify the usual pain points of
Shopify，以往
launching products online disapp appear
在线发布产品时遇到的痛点将
completely no matter the size of your
完全消失。无论你的企业规模大小，
business Shopify has everything you need
Shopify 都能提供你所需的一切，助你将
to make your business go to the next
业务提升到新的
level and better connect with your
高度，更好地与
customers all over the world to say
世界各地的客户建立联系。
thank you to all of you for listening to
感谢大家收听
my show we're giving you a trial which
我的节目。 我们提供试用，
is just $1 a month you can sign up by
每月只需 1 美元。您可以访问
Bartlet that's shopify.com Bartlet or
shopify.com Bartlet 注册，或者
find the link in the description
在下方说明中找到链接。
below and for people that have
对于那些有
food addictions and binge eating
食物成瘾和暴食
problems the ketogenic diet I guess it's
问题的人来说，生酮饮食或许能帮
knocking you off that roller coaster
你摆脱这种过山车般的进食体验。
what well being in a state of ketosis is
处于酮症状态能帮
knocking you off that roller coaster of
你摆脱这种对食物的
craving eating craving eating craving
渴望，这种说法
eating is that accurate is that what
准确吗？是的，
it's doing yes so um the ketogenic diet
生酮饮食
by lowering and stabilizing glucose and
通过降低和稳定血糖和
insulin levels the thing about insulin
胰岛素水平来发挥作用。
is that a lot of people think about
很多人认为胰岛素的作用是调节血糖，也就是
when your glucose goes up the insulin
血糖升高时胰岛素会
brings it down and and that's true but
降低血糖。这没错，但这只是
roles that insulin has it's the one it's
胰岛素众多重要作用之一，也是它
most famous for but the thing that uh
最广为人知的功能。但
what is not well known is that insulin
鲜为人知的是，胰岛素的作用
is so much more than a blood sugar
远不止
regulator it's actually a master
调节血糖，它实际上是一种重要的
metabolic hormone and it's regulating
代谢激素。 它调节着
the activity of every cell in the body
体内每个细胞的活动。
every cell has an insulin receptor on
每个细胞表面都有胰岛素受体，
its surface multiple insulin receptors
多个胰岛素受体
to pay attention to the insulin level in
监测着血液中的胰岛素水平。
so uh when you're on a glucose and
所以，当你的血糖和
Insulin roller
胰岛素水平像坐过山车一样波动时，问题就出现了。
begins insulin is talking to and
胰岛素会与
activity of many other hormones in the
血液中许多其他激素相互作用，控制它们的水平和活性，
blood including stress hormones like
包括压力激素（如
adrenaline and cortisol um reproductive
肾上腺素和皮质醇）、生殖
hormones like estrogen and testost
激素（如雌激素和睾酮）、
cherone your blood pressure regulating
血压调节
hormones your satiety hormones the
激素、饱腹激素（
hormones that make you feel full after
让你饭后感到饱腹的激素）、
you eat your hunger hormones so many
饥饿激素等等。许多
other hormones are on this roller
其他激素都参与了这种
coaster uh that you're unstable from
波动，导致你
within and people often will think well
体内的激素水平不稳定。人们常常会想：“
I'm stressed and that's why I'm eating I
我压力很大，所以我才吃东西。我
I I feel really anxious um I get
感觉很焦虑，很烦躁，很饿，
need to eat and then I feel better and
需要吃东西，然后感觉好多了。”
that's true they will they will feel
这没错，他们会感觉
better for a few hours
好几个小时，
but what what happens four to five hours
但是四五个小时
later if they've eaten something that's
后会发生什么呢？如果他们吃了一些东西……
spiked their glucose and Insulin again
他们的血糖和胰岛素水平再次飙升，
is they're going to get there's this
他们又会……有一项
great study with um healthy teenage boys
很棒的研究，研究对象是
they took healthy teenage boys and they
健康的青少年男孩。研究人员
gave them either a sugar-free
让他们分别喝无糖无咖啡因可乐
Cola uh caffeine-free or a caffeine-free
和加糖无咖啡因可乐。喝
Cola sweetened with sugar and the boys
加糖可乐的男孩，
quadrupled four to five hours after
在喝完四到五个小时后，肾上腺素水平（压力激素）翻了四倍，
drinking the soda and the boys who drank
而喝
the other soda stayed flat it's the food
另一种可乐的男孩，肾上腺素水平则保持不变。是食物导致了
that's causing the stress that's causing
压力，压力又反过来控制了
the food eating you so there's this
食物，形成了一个
vicious cycle if people understood that
恶性循环。如果人们理解了这一点，就会明白
most of what's happening there it's not
大部分原因。
your fault that you want to overeat
你想吃太多食物并不是你的错，
those Foods they are designed to be
这些食物的设计就是为了让你过量食用。
overeaten like chemical Engineers these
就像化学工程师一样，
this is very very intelligent um
这是一种非常非常聪明的
engineering that's going on very clever
工程技术。
if you make it irresistible and if you
如果你让产品令人无法抗拒，你就能卖出更多；如果你
make it
让产品
unsatisfying how many people feel that
不满足，你就会卖得更多。有多少人觉得
they can't control their consumption of
自己无法控制某些食物的摄入量？
certain foods that's by Design if you if
如果
you want to keep eating it you'll buy
你想继续吃，你就会买
more of it if you eat real
更多。但如果你吃真正的
food you have to stop after a little
食物，过一段时间你就必须停下来。
while they're so satisfying things like
它们确实很令人满足，比如
meat Seafood poultry eggs fruit veget
肉类、海鲜、家禽、鸡蛋、水果、
Veges even fruits fruits some people
蔬菜，甚至水果。有些人
will overeat fruit but but fruit has
会吃过量水果，但水果含有
fiber it has water it's really hard to
纤维和水分，很难控制
eat you know 10 pieces of
自己吃下10个
fruit very easy to drink you know a
水果。喝果汁很容易，
bottle of several bottles of fruit juice
一瓶或几瓶果汁也很容易。
very easy um to eat multiple packages of
吃好几包
candy because those what happens with
糖果也很容易，因为这些都是
ultr processed carbohydrates these
超加工碳水化合物，也就是
refined carbohydrates they blow past
精制碳水化合物造成的。它们会绕过
your hormonal stop signs and that's not
你的激素信号，这不是
your fault but if you understand that
你的错。但如果你明白
that's what's happening then you can
发生了什么，你就可以
takes a few days you got to step away
花几天时间远离
from them but but on the other side is
它们。但另一方面，你会获得
tremendous freedom and
巨大的自由和
control the gentleman you mentioned in
控制力。你
that case study a second ago you
刚才在案例研究中提到的那位先生，你
referred to as Carl which I guess is a
称他为卡尔，我猜这是个化名。
cloaked name um he's the one that had
他患有
the bipolar disorder uh no Carl is a
双相情感障碍。不，卡尔的
different case ah okay tell me about Co
情况不一样。好的，跟我说说科吧。是的，
yeah so I opened the book with the story
我以卡尔的故事作为本书的开篇。
ofl Carl who has you know generously
一位慷慨地
allowed me to share his story um a
允许我分享他故事的人，一位
mid-60s who had had lifelong depression
六十多岁的绅士，他一生都饱受抑郁症
and
和
anxiety and uh for years he he didn't
焦虑症的折磨。多年来，他一直没有
seek any treatment and then maybe about
寻求任何治疗。大约在
15 years or so before he consulted with
十五年前，他来咨询
me he went to an A A psychiat A
我之前，去了一家
Psychiatry specialty clinic for some
精神病专科诊所，做了一些
specialized brain Imaging and uh
特殊的脑部影像检查、全面的
extensive evaluation and lots and lots
评估以及大量的
of specialized tests and he left the
专业测试。离开
clinic with thousands of dollars later
诊所时，他花费了数千美元，被
with three diagnosis depression anxiety
诊断出患有抑郁症、焦虑症
and ADHD and three prescriptions one for
和注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD），并拿到了三种处方药：一种治疗抑郁症，
depression one for anxiety one for ADHD
一种治疗焦虑症，一种治疗ADHD。
so he started those
他开始服用这些
medications and his depression got a lot
药物，抑郁症症状有所
better but he then uh had a brand new
好转。但是，他又遇到了一个全新的
problem on his hands which was he was
问题：他开始
becoming Manic and he had never had
出现躁狂症状，而他以前从未有过
Mania before so he was been
躁狂症。他变得
uncharacteristically um energetic and uh
异常精力充沛，易怒
um uh irritable and unpleasant and so it
且令人不快。
was changing it was changing his
他的
character his personality a certain his
性格、人格以及
behavior in a certain way that was
行为方式都发生了改变，这在
becoming very unpleasant at work and at
工作和生活中都变得非常令人不快。
home so he then turned to marijuana to
于是，他开始寻求帮助。 他一开始
try to take the edge off developed a
想用大麻来缓解压力，结果却染上了
marijuana addiction now he's got another
大麻瘾。现在他又有了另一个
problem and so he thought to himself you
问题，于是他心想：
know this isn't this isn't what I signed
这不是我想要的，这不是我想要的。
up for I was trying to solve a problem
我本来只是想解决一个问题，
and now I've got two new problems on my
现在却又多了两个问题。
hands so he took himself off the
所以他停了
medications and said you know I I I
药，说：“我
can't use medication medications is not
不能用药，药不适合
for me I'm going to try to manage my
我。我要通过严格的锻炼来控制我的
mood issues my depression anxiety with
情绪问题、抑郁和焦虑，
rigorous exercise I'm going to let
我要让
exercise be my medicine and he started
锻炼成为我的良药。”他开始
cycling uh bikes over a 100 miles a week
骑自行车，每周骑行超过100英里。
and it actually helped a lot it didn't
这确实很有帮助，虽然没有
completely resolve all of the symptoms
完全消除所有症状，
but it brought them down to um a very
但确实把它们降到了一个可以
manageable level uh for years so
控制的水平，而且持续了好几年。所以
exercise was his medicine exercise
锻炼成了他的良药，锻炼可以
improves metabolic health and so he was
改善新陈代谢。他
still eating a standard American diet
仍然保持着标准的美国饮食，
before and then um what happened is as
以前从未尝试过任何饮食改变。后来，
he entered his 60s the depression
到了60多岁，抑郁和
anxiety started to rise in the
焦虑开始复发，
background exercise wasn't working quite
锻炼的效果也不如以前了。就在
before he met with me something
他来见我之前，发生了一些事。
stressful it happened at work and it was
压力很大，这件事发生在工作中，
essentially a shift in his job
主要是因为他的工作
description which was making him anxious
内容发生了变化，这让他感到焦虑。
and he started experiencing very
他开始
suddenly these bouts of um agitation and
突然出现一阵阵的烦躁、
anxiety and restlessness and exercise
焦虑和坐立不安。运动
being his medicine he would he would
是他的良药，他会
cycle on the weekends
在周末骑自行车，
and at night if it was a if it was it
如果是在
was happening on a week night a work
工作日的晚上，
night he would be walking because he
他就会步行，因为
couldn't bike at night when it was dark
天黑后他无法骑车。
he would walk sometimes eight even 25
他有时会走8英里甚至25
miles to try to get rid of this excess
英里，试图消耗掉多余的
energy and he said I don't have time for
精力。他说：“我没时间做
this I can't exercise enough to keep my
这些了，我运动量不够，无法
symptoms under control he didn't know
控制我的症状。”他不知道
what else to do he starts searching
还能做什么，于是开始在
online for Solutions came across
网上寻找解决办法。他偶然发现了
information about carnivore diets and
关于食肉饮食和
mental health contacted me for a consult
心理健康的信息，联系我咨询，说：“
and said I want to try the carnivore
我想尝试食肉
diet for my for my
饮食来缓解我的
anxiety and I mean there were lots of
焦虑。”当然，
other things we could have done uh to
我们还可以做很多其他事情来
improve the quality of his diet but this
改善他的饮食质量，但
is what he wanted to do because he was
他想尝试食肉饮食，因为他
hoping that would bring him the most the
希望这能给他带来最大、
the fastest relief so switched to a
最快的缓解。于是他开始采用
carnivore diet 3 to four pounds of fatty
食肉饮食，每天吃3到4磅
meat per day mostly pork and beef this
肥肉。 他每天主要吃猪肉和牛肉，
was dairy free no plants and uh he
不吃乳制品，也不吃植物。他
checked his ketones using urine testing
用尿酮检测法检查酮体，
which Which is less expensive than blood
这种方法比血液
testing uh he's in mild ketosis every
检测便宜。他每天都用尿酮试纸检测酮体，结果显示他处于轻度酮症状态。到了
to improve by week three by week six his
第三周，他的情况开始好转；到了第六周，他
score was zero on all his depression and
的所有抑郁和
anxiety scales he had no
焦虑量表得分都降到了零。他完全没有
symptoms at all of of depression anxiety
抑郁和焦虑的症状，
not just of those recent extreme
不仅是最近出现的那些严重
symptoms that he was experiencing but
症状，还有他
life that had never completely resolved
一生中从未彻底解决过的那些症状。
before so he said you know I I this is
他说：“你知道吗？我这辈子从来
the I've never felt this well in my
没有感觉这么好过。”
entire life and so this is the power of
这就是
these strategies is they don't just
这些策略的力量所在：它们不仅仅是
reduce symptoms a little bit they
减轻一些症状，它们
actually have the power to heal the
实际上有能力治愈
underlying problem in ways that I mean
根本问题。
this is a phrase I've heard so many
我听过太多次这样的话了：“
times I feel better than I've ever felt
我感觉比我这辈子任何时候都好。”
people generally that was in
通常情况下，你不会在给别人开药的时候听到这种话。那是
2019 was it uh I couldn't tell you what
2019年，是吗？我记不清是哪
year but that sounds right how is he
一年了，但听起来没错。他
doing now yeah I mean we we are still we
现在怎么样了？嗯，我们仍然……我们仍然…… 他们
times a year he's doing very well in
每年都会联系几次，他现在状态非常好。事实上，
about what happened with this diet is
关于这种饮食方式，有趣的一点是，在
that during that long period of of
那段长时间的
intermittent
间歇性
agitation uh he you know he's a very
躁动期间，他
physically fit guy because of all the
因为经常锻炼，身体非常健康，
exercise and he and he was lean he lost
而且很精瘦。
10 pounds during that period of
在那段躁动期间，他减掉了10磅，而这些体重是
agitation that he could not afford to
他不能承受的。
lose when he first started working with
他刚开始和
me he was underweight
我合作时体重过轻，
and despite eating four pounds of fatty
尽管每天吃4磅
meat per day he couldn't regain that 10
肥肉，但他还是无法恢复那10
pounds unless we added uh back some
磅，除非我们
carbohydrate into the diet this is
在他的饮食中重新添加一些碳水化合物。
really this is a subtle point but for
这一点非常微妙，但对于
athletes sometimes especially in the
运动员来说，尤其是在
transition um there needs to be a
过渡期的早期阶段，饮食
certain amount of carbohydrate in the
中需要一定量的碳水化合物来
diet um to support high performance he
支持高水平的运动表现。他并
didn't stay on the carnivore diet no he
没有一直坚持纯肉饮食，他
did not so he was on the car carnivore
没有。他坚持纯肉
diet for many months and then be but
饮食好几个月，但
because he couldn't regain that weight I
因为他无法恢复体重，所以我
asked him I said well you know I think
问他，我说，我觉得
we need to put some carbohydrate in to
我们需要添加一些碳水化合物来
help you uh regain this weight and so I
帮助你。 体重反弹了，所以我
asked him which foods he missed the most
问他最想念哪些食物，
from and the things he missed most were
并给他列了一份全食物清单供他选择。他最想念的是
uh potatoes and yogurt so some starchy
土豆和酸奶，还有一些淀粉类
root vegetables some plain unsweetened
根茎蔬菜和原味无糖
yogurt um up to about 100 grams of
酸奶。每天摄入大约100克
carbohydrate per day seemed to be about
碳水化合物似乎比较
right for the days when he was e excuse
合适，尤其是在他锻炼的日子里。如果
me exercising on the days when he wasn't
不
exercising he would cut it back so he
锻炼，他就会减少碳水化合物的摄入量，根据
was tailoring it to his personal energy
自己的能量
needs and so so this is another um uh
需求进行调整。所以，关于
for him is that um I mean his his scales
他的情况，还有一件很有趣的事情：他的体重秤上的数字
are still at zero but he has been uh as
仍然是零，但正如
we've talked to each other on and off
我们这些
over the years he has been able to make
年来断断续续的交流，他一直在
adjustments to his diet understanding
调整自己的饮食，理解其中的
the principles if you understand the
原则。如果你理解了这些
principles then you know which changes
原则，你就知道哪些改变
you can get away with and which changes
可以接受，哪些改变
you can't and he has stayed well there's
不能接受。他一直保持着健康。
a couple of key things people always
人们一
talk about when they hear the carnival
听到“嘉年华
diet the first is they say there's
减肥法”就会提到几个关键点，首先是他们说这种
nutritional deficiencies to the diet
饮食存在营养不足的问题。 纯肉饮食
that aren't like sustainable so if you
并不可持续，所以如果你
eliminate certain food groups like
剔除某些食物类别，比如
fibers vitamin C's vitamin E magnesiums
纤维、维生素C、维生素E、镁
Etc then which are essential
等等这些必需
nutrients then you're going to have
营养素，就会出现
problems so a carnivore diet
问题。理论上，纯肉饮食
theoretically does provide all essential
可以提供所有必需
nutrients so if you look at what is
营养素。如果你仔细研究
inside animal Foods you will find all
动物性食物的成分，你会发现所有
essential nutrients you can't say that
必需营养素都包含在内。你不能说
of any plant food there's not a plant
任何植物性食物都含有所有必需营养素，
food on Earth that can that provides all
地球上没有任何一种植物性食物可以提供所有
essential nutrients animal foods can uh
必需营养素。动物性食物可以，比如肉类、
I would say meet Seafood poultry eggs
海鲜、家禽和鸡蛋，它们
are missing a couple of nutrients and
缺少一些营养素，
dairy is missing even more um but uh
乳制品缺少的营养素更多。但是，
meat seafood and poultry contain every
肉类、海鲜和家禽包含了
nutrient we need the question is how
我们所需的所有营养素。问题是，
much do you need like fiber oh well
你需要多少纤维？
fiber is not a nutrient oh okay but do
纤维本身并不是营养素。好吧，但是
you get fibr in a carnivore diet there
纯肉饮食能提供纤维吗？
are different definitions of carnivore
纯肉饮食有不同的定义，
but the strictest sort of purest
但最严格、最纯粹的
definition of carnivore is animal Foods
定义是只吃动物性食物，
only and fiber comes from plants so it's
纤维来自植物，所以它
fiber free a true carnivore diet is
不含纤维。真正的纯肉饮食是
fiber free so could you lost on a true
不含纤维的。那么，纯
carnivore diet without getting some kind
肉饮食会导致
of like microbiome issue or some kind of
肠道菌群失衡吗？ 或者说，
because you need fiber right why thought
因为你需要纤维，对吧？为什么人们认为
it was good for like digestion and your
它对消化、肠道
microbiome and stuff like that what does
菌群等等都有好处？它到底有什么作用？
it do a lot of people tell me that it
很多人告诉我，纤维会
prevents glucose going into the blood or
阻止葡萄糖进入血液，或者说，
something where's the glucose coming
葡萄糖是从哪里来的？
from so you don't need it fiber fiber is
所以你不需要纤维？纤维
very helpful and I spell this out in the
非常有用，我在书中详细阐述了这一点。
book so because there's we have a lot of
因为我们
Hal truths in our minds about food um
脑海中有很多关于食物的半真半假的想法，
even people who are paying really close
即使是那些非常
attention to the to nutrition
关注营养
science have a lot of half-truths in
科学的人，脑海中也有很多
their minds about food so yes fiber for
关于食物的半真半假的想法。所以，
example you're exactly right lowers
比如，你说得完全正确，纤维可以降低
glucose spikes but the glucose is coming
血糖峰值，但这些葡萄糖
from a diet that's too high and sugar
来自高糖饮食，所以
and so you won't get glucose spikes if
如果你控制好血糖水平，就不会出现血糖峰值。
so that's one uh interesting thing about
这是纤维的一个有趣之处。
fiber so if you're eating a high
如果你吃的是高
carbohydrate diet fiber can soften your
碳水化合物饮食，纤维可以缓和
glucose spikes and that's a plus but
血糖峰值，这是一个优点，但
there's a more effective way to lower
降低血糖峰值更有效的方法
your glucose spikes is to not get a
是从一开始就避免
glucose spike in the first place um and
血糖峰值，
that may not require taking all the
这可能并不需要完全
carbohydrate out of your diet it might
去除碳水化合物。 调整饮食可能
just mean lowering it to your personal
意味着降低摄入量到你个人的
tolerance um another thing people often
耐受水平。人们常说的
say about fiber is that it sweeps your
关于膳食纤维的另一点是，它能
colon clean of toxins and kind of um um
清除结肠内的毒素，这些毒素
and uh that might otherwise build up and
可能会堆积并
cause problems but fiber um there's no
引发问题。但是，没有任何
evidence that fiber is sweeping anything
证据表明膳食纤维具有清除毒素的作用，
clean or there's never been a study that
也从未有任何研究
demonstrates this it's really just a
证实这一点。这实际上只是一种
belief about what we imagine fibers
误解，我们想象膳食纤维
being like the broom of the intestines
就像肠道的扫帚，
but there's no that that's just a belief
但事实并非如此，这只是一种误解，
there's no science behind that
没有任何科学依据。
whatsoever um the the intestines clean
肠道会自我清洁，肠道
themselves the lining sheds regularly
内壁会定期脱落，
actually very frequently and has and the
实际上非常频繁，
border of the intestines um sweep
肠道边缘也会
themselves clean so they the intestine
自我清洁。所以肠道
knows how to take care of itself that
知道如何以这种方式照顾自己。
way but the biggest myth about fiber is
但关于膳食纤维最大的误解是
that it's good for digestion because
它有益于消化，因为
fiber by definition is
根据定义，膳食纤维是
indigestible by humans so there are two
人体无法消化的。膳食纤维有两种：
kinds of fiber there's soluble and
可溶性纤维和
insoluble and the soluble is um you know
不溶性纤维。可溶性纤维
the kind that holds water it's like in
就像苹果中的那种可以吸收水分的纤维，而不溶性纤维则……
an apple and the insoluble is the kind
那种
might find in like broccoli for example
像西兰花里常见的坚韧、纤维状、木质的东西，
so the soluble fiber the bacteria and
可溶性纤维，
the lower parts of our intestine can
我们肠道的细菌和下段可以
ferment that to a certain extent um but
一定程度上发酵它，但是，但是，但是，但是，但是，但是，
uh but then we but then we can't make
但是，我们不能
use of the sugars that it's releasing um
利用…… 它释放的糖分，嗯，就在
right here fiber traditionally
这里。纤维，传统上
considered essential for feeding
被认为是滋养
beneficial gut bacteria and promoting
有益肠道细菌和促进
regular bowel movements yes okay so a
规律排便所必需的。好的，
couple of things to unpack there so one
这里有几点需要解释。首先，
is that the uh a lot of people uh there
很多人，有
are quite a few papers on this uh
很多论文都
claiming that we need fiber because we
声称我们需要纤维，因为我们
need to feed our cells butyrate which is
需要为细胞提供丁酸，丁酸是
a breakdown product of fiber but
纤维的分解产物。但是，
butyrate if you think about what a
如果你想想什么
ketone is it's beta hydroxy vate feeds
是酮，丁酸（β-羟基酸）也能很好地滋养
the intestinal cells just as well so you
肠道细胞。所以，你
don't need to eat fiber to feed your
不需要吃纤维来为
cell's butyrate if you think that the
细胞提供丁酸。如果你认为
cells need butyrate then you can get it
细胞需要丁酸，你可以
from a ketogenic diet um so I explained
通过生酮饮食来获取。我
that in the book too is that there's
在书中也解释过，
more than one way to generate that
生成这种分子的方法不止一种。
molecule can someone exist on the
有人能在不补充任何营养的情况下，长期坚持
carnivore diet like the extreme version
纯肉饮食（比如极端版本
of the carnivore diet for a long time
的纯肉饮食）吗？
supplementation so you we really don't
我们真的不
know and we really don't have any
知道，我们也没有任何
long-term data on on any dietary pattern
关于任何饮食模式的长期数据。
I think this is really important for
我认为这一点对人们来说非常重要。
criticism of diets that we feel
批评那些让我们感到
uncomfortable with or might be worried
不舒服或担忧的饮食方式，
about like ketogenic diets or carnivore
比如生酮饮食或食肉
diets because they're so different from
饮食，是很常见的，因为它们与
what we're told we're supposed to eat
我们被告知应该吃的食物截然不同，所以会引发
there's a lot of fear and worry uh about
很多恐惧和担忧。于是人们会
them and so think well okay it's it's um
想，好吧，
it's normalized my blood sugar level I
它让我的血糖水平恢复正常（我
used to have type two diabetes um you
以前患有二型糖尿病），
I've lost 50 pounds um my depression
我减掉了50磅，我的抑郁症
went away um my uh I normalized my
消失了，我的
coronary artery calcium scores I'm at
冠状动脉钙化评分恢复正常，我患
lower risk for cardiovascular disease my
心血管疾病的风险降低了，我的
triglycerides came down um you know I
甘油三酯也下降了，你知道，我
feel better I'm I in every way like all
感觉更好了，我各方面都感觉更好了，我的所有
of my health markers have improved and
健康指标都改善了。
so when you show people study after
所以，当你向人们展示一项又一项关于生
study after study of a ketogenic diet um
酮饮食的研究，证明它能
improving multiple aspects of metabolic
改善代谢
health and physical health and mental
健康、身体健康和心理
health it's cured my seizures it's cured
健康的多个方面，它治愈了我的癫痫，治愈了
my bipo whatever it was the only the
我的双相情感障碍等等，
somebody could say is well well yes okay
人们最后可能会说，好吧，
it's made you extraordinarily healthy
它让你现在非常健康。
now but I wonder what's going to happen
我想知道
20 years from now MH nobody can tell you
20年后会发生什么，MH，没人能告诉你，
that because there's no way you could
因为你不可能
design a 20 year long study of any diet
设计一个长达20年的研究来评估任何一种饮食。
so you could say this about the
你可以这样评价
Mediterranean diet you could say this
地中海饮食，你可以这样评价
about a carnivore diet you could say
食肉饮食，你可以
this about a vegan diet well vegan diet
这样评价纯素饮食。纯素饮食如果
unsupplemented is is fatal um it's it
不补充营养，是致命的，因为它
has dangerous nutritional holes so why
存在危险的营养缺陷。那么，为什么
aren't we saying this about vegan diets
我们不这样评价纯素饮食呢？
when we can look at a vegan diet and see
我们明明可以观察纯素饮食，发现
that it that that it's incompatible with
它与
human life unless you eat fortified
人类生命不相容，除非你食用强化
processed foods or supplement which most
加工食品或补充剂，而
people in the world cannot do um we look
世界上大多数人都做不到这一点。我们再来看看
at a carnivore diet and you can actually
食肉饮食，你会发现你可以
find all of the nutrients in these
在这些动物性食物中找到所有必需的营养，
animal foods and that's the diet that
而这才是
you're more worried about because
你更担心的饮食，因为
theoretically
理论上，
longterm something bad might happen now
长期食用可能会产生不良后果。
I am not at all saying
我并不是说
that a carnivore diet is the right diet
食肉饮食适合
for everybody um or that it's even the
所有人，或者说它适合
right approach for everybody to consider
所有人，
but I think we have to keep an open mind
但我认为我们必须保持开放的心态，
and stay curious and look at the biology
保持好奇心，研究
of food and allow people to make their
食物的生物学特性，并允许人们…… 我个人在
own I'm nutritionally pro-choice which
营养选择方面是支持的，这
means I would if you came to me with a
意味着如果你因为
mental health issue um I would support
心理健康问题来找我，我会支持
you in optimizing the diet of your
你优化你
choice and making it as brain healthy as
选择的饮食，并尽可能地让它对大脑健康有益，
I possibly could because I because uh
因为……
it's very important that you feel
你
comfortable with the diet that you're
对自己的饮食感到舒适非常重要，
eating and so there are lots of ways to
有很多方法可以
do that but I think it's really
做到这一点，但我认为这真的很
important and one thing I encourage
重要。
people to do in my work and in my book
在我的工作和书中，我鼓励人们敞开
is to open our minds and get curious
心扉，
about food the biology of food the
对食物、食物的生物学、
biology of the brain because most of
大脑的生物学产生好奇心，因为
what we hear about nutrition doesn't
我们听到的关于营养的大部分信息并非
come from biology it doesn't come from
来自生物学，并非来自临床实验，也并非来自关于
about how cells work or about what's
细胞如何运作或
actually inside food it comes from this
食物内部成分的信息，而是来自一种
type of study called A nutrition
叫做营养流行病学的研究，这种研究
epidemiology study which is just
只是基于
questionnaire based guesswork untested
问卷调查的猜测，是未经检验的
theories about what we should eat most
理论，关于我们应该吃什么。
of what we believe about nutrition is
我们对营养的大部分认知都是
untested theories wild guesses and
未经检验的理论、胡乱猜测和
Wishful
一厢情愿的
Thinking many of the people that choose
想法。许多选择
a keto diet do it for very sort of
生酮饮食的人都是出于非常
superficial reasons sure you know I
肤浅的原因。当然，你知道，我
think it's probably one of the reasons
认为 这可能是
why I do it once a year um for a couple
我每年进行一次生酮饮食（持续
of weeks um why does it help you to lose
几周）的原因之一。为什么它能帮助你
weight is that again just because of
减肥呢？还是因为
restriction so it's insulin so it it
限制卡路里摄入，也就是胰岛素的作用。所以，
everybody out there who's trying to lose
所有正在尝试
weight they need to know one thing and
减肥的人都需要知道一点，那就是
works if you cannot burn fat if your
如果你无法燃烧脂肪，你的
insulin levels are too high so if you
胰岛素水平过高，那么生酮饮食就有效。如果你
know what rais
知道如何降低
insulin you can lo you can turn that
胰岛素水平，你就可以
insulin knob down if you know how to do
降低胰岛素水平。如果你知道如何做到这一点，
that you will lose weight it's a
你就能减肥，这是一个
biological fact so when you turn down
生物学事实。当你降低
insulin you will burn fat so a ketogenic
胰岛素水平时，你就会燃烧脂肪。生酮
diet you can't produce ketones unless
饮食中，除非你的胰岛素水平足够低，否则你无法产生酮体。酮体检测
the ketones on that meter are showing
仪上的酮体数值表明
you that you are burning fat you can't
你正在燃烧脂肪，除非你燃烧脂肪，否则你无法
make ketones unless you're burning fat
产生酮体。
so you can't you really cannot burn fat
所以，除非你处于酮症状态，否则你真的无法燃烧脂肪。
unless you're in ketosis you don't
你
necessar have to be in ketosis all the
不一定需要一直处于酮症状态，也不
time you don't necessarily have to have
一定需要
very high Ketone levels but if you're
很高的酮体水平，但如果你
not in ketosis you're not burning fat so
不处于酮症状态，你就无法燃烧脂肪。所以，如果你不处于酮症状态，你就无法燃烧脂肪。
um if you're not in ketosis the brain
在酮症状态下，大脑
can't even see that you've got energy
甚至无法感知你体内有
spare energy to burn you might have 200
剩余能量可以燃烧。你可能体内
300 pounds of stored energy as fat the
储存了200到300磅的脂肪，但
brain will still ask you to eat to eat
大脑仍然会要求你摄入
more carbohydrate because it's not in
更多碳水化合物，因为它没有进入
fat burning mode so it's in car
燃脂模式，而是处于
carbohydrate burning mode when it's
碳水化合物燃烧模式。当它感到
hungry it's going to look for more
饥饿时，就会寻找更多
carbohydrate you have to you have to
碳水化合物。你必须
teach it you have to bring your body
教会它，必须让你的身体
into fat burning mode and and train your
进入燃脂模式，并训练你的
body give your cell some time a few
身体。给你的细胞一些时间，
weeks to learn how to burn fat again and
几周的时间，让它重新学习如何燃烧脂肪并
stay there my mother is 91 years old she
保持这种状态。我的母亲91岁了，她
has lost 50 pounds on a ketogenic diet
通过生酮饮食减掉了50磅。
it is never too late to all she has to
永远都不算晚，她只需要
do is make sure those there are ketones
确保她的血糖
on her meter when her glucose meter was
仪上有酮体即可。当她的血糖仪读数
nice and stable she wasn't losing
稳定时，她却没有
weight because the insulin was still too
减肥，因为胰岛素水平仍然
high the ketones tell you the ketones
过高。酮体可以告诉你，酮体水平
are essentially a mirror image of your
本质上反映了你的
insulin level so we don't have a home
胰岛素水平。虽然我们目前还没有家用
insulin level test yet we
胰岛素水平测试，但我们
have fabulous continuous glucose
有非常棒的连续血糖
monitors which I recommend anybody out
监测仪，我建议任何有
there with a mental health issue or
心理健康或
physical anybody out there who can
身体健康问题的人，任何能够
afford $5 or $50 for a single two week
负担得起5美元的人，都去买一个。 一个两周的
glucose sensor which are now available
血糖传感器就要50美元，现在
in the United States over the counter
在美国可以非处方购买了，
which they weren't before um I think
以前是买不到的。嗯，我想
you've had them in the UK for a lot
英国人早就有了。
longer you can see what your glucose
你可以用它来观察你的血糖
levels are doing in response to your
水平如何随着你的
lifestyle your food choices your
生活方式、饮食选择、
exercise Etc they can't it can't tell
运动等等而变化。它不能告诉
you what's going on with your insulin
你胰岛素水平的变化，所以即使你的
stable glucose level nice in the healthy
血糖水平非常稳定，处于健康
range your insulin can still be too high
范围内，你的胰岛素水平仍然可能过高，
and you still might just be you're
你可能仍然在
burning all that glucose for energy
燃烧葡萄糖来获取能量。
a ketone meter will tell you if you're
酮体仪可以告诉你你是否在
burning fat I'm on Amazon now it says
燃烧脂肪。我现在在亚马逊上，它标价
sort of $50 or yeah there's ones for $40
50美元，或者也有40美元的，还有
as well yeah one for $30 as well yeah
30美元的。嗯，
interesting okay think I'm going to try
有意思。好吧，我想我会试试。
one I've never actually done one before
我以前从来没用过，
so I I guess I didn't really know if I
所以我猜我不太清楚自己是否
was in ktis ketosis or not but I just oh
处于生酮状态。但是，哦，
it's so useful because um uh if you're
它真的很有用，因为如果你
if you're following a ketogenic diet um
正在进行生酮饮食，那么
the thing that makes it ketogenic is the
生酮饮食的关键在于……
ketones yeah and so I you were telling
酮体，是的，所以你
me before before we started recording
之前跟我说过，在我们开始录音之前，
that um you're always looking up okay
你总是查
which foods are keto which foods aren't
哪些食物是生酮食物，哪些不是。
keto and it's really not so much about
其实没那么重要，
ketogenic diet if you if you understand
如果你了解生酮饮食，
you know how much to have and when um
知道该吃多少、什么时候吃，几乎什么都可以吃。总之，
and but uh uh in any case um the Ketone
酮体
meter will tell you you're in ketosis
检测仪会告诉你是否处于酮症状态，
and if you're not in ketosis you can
如果没有，你可以
tweak your your plant so all of this is
调整饮食。这些内容都
in the book but um but you can the
在书里，但是，生
about a ketogenic diet is getting into
酮饮食最重要的就是
good consistent daily ketosis for at
至少连续六周保持良好的、稳定的每日酮症状态，这样才能
straight that sends the daily signal to
向
your cells we're burning fat now we're
细胞发出“我们正在
burning fat now we need to learn how to
燃烧脂肪”的信号。我们需要学习如何
burn fat there are enzyme systems and
燃烧脂肪，这需要酶系统、
Pathways and cells that need to ramp
通路和细胞的激活，而
up and and that takes time so it takes a
这需要时间。
while for the body and brain to kind of
身体和大脑需要一段时间才能重新
learn how to burn fat again and uh it
学习如何燃烧脂肪，这
doesn't happen
不会
overnight in terms of energy there are
一蹴而就。至于能量方面，
so many reasons why I'm a big matcha fan
我非常喜欢抹茶，原因有很多。
if you don't already know by now and so
你可能已经知道了，
much so that I actually invested in the
我甚至投资了
UK's leading matcha company called
英国领先的抹茶公司
perfect Ted and one of my favorite
Perfect Ted。我最喜欢的
perfect T products is these delicious
Perfect T 产品之一就是这些美味的
matcha pouches that come in every flavor
抹茶粉，口味丰富，
from salted caramel to Peach flavor to
从咸焦糖到桃子味、
mint flavor to Berry flavor one of my
薄荷味、浆果味应有尽有。我最
favorites is this vanilla flavor which
喜欢的是香草味，
I'm going to make in just just two
我马上就来教你，只需两
seconds you just take this mixer here
秒钟就能搞定。你只需要拿起这个搅拌器，
get a little bit of the powder pop it on
舀一点抹茶粉，
top of the shaker like that put the lid
像这样倒进搅拌杯里，盖上盖子，
on shake shake
摇摇摇，
shake delicious if you haven't tried
美味极了！如果你还没试过，
this yet you can find perfect Ted at
可以在
Tesco and Holland Barrett stores or
Tesco 和 Holland Barrett 门店找到 Perfect Ted，或者
online where you can get 40% off with my
在线购买，使用我的优惠码 diary 40 可以享受 40% 的折扣。
code diary 40 head to perfect ted.com
访问 perfectted.com，
and put in code diary 40 to try this
输入优惠码 diary 40 即可体验这款
delicious multi-flavored match now
美味的多口味抹茶粉。
highly recommend and if you do it please
强烈推荐！如果你试了，请记得
tag me send me a message
标记我，或者给我发个消息。
online what part of your work sort of
你的工作中哪些部分与
overlays with psychology you know when
心理学相关？你知道，当
someone comes to you and they they're
有人来找你，他们正
experiencing some anxiety or depression
经历焦虑、抑郁
or something and they they're describing
或其他问题，并描述
their life and their life is full of
他们的生活时，你会怎么做？ 他们的生活充满了
trauma and hard things and they got
创伤和苦难，他们还
fired from their job it seems a little
丢了工作，在这种时候跟
bit peculiar to talk to them about diet
他们谈论饮食似乎有点奇怪。
did do you ever think first about like
你有没有想过先给他们开
some kind of psychological
一些心理
prescription oh you know I got some my
处方？你知道，我
training at Cambridge hospital uh in
在剑桥医院接受的
psychiatric residency is very
精神科住院医师培训非常
Psychotherapy focused I got really
注重心理治疗，我接受了非常
excellent training in Psychotherapy and
好的心理治疗培训，而且
I still use it every day in my work it
我每天都在工作中运用它。
we're not throwing the baby out with the
我们并不是因噎废食，
bath water here in fact the psychology
事实上，
of people's relationship with food is
人们与食物之间的心理关系
really important to address I mean most
非常重要。我的意思是，
of what I do I mean I could I could
我所做的大部分工作，我可以
teach you in an hour um everything you
在一小时内教会你所有关于
needed to know about why you should
为什么你应该
switch to a ketogenic diet for mental
为了心理健康而改用生酮饮食的知识，
health and and I could give you a little
我可以给你一张小
sheet and you could go off and do it
纸条，然后你就可以照着做了，对吧？那样的话，
right I would I would be rapidly
我很快就会
obsolete um which would be a good
过时了，这当然是个幸福的
problem to have right um but what
烦恼，对吧？但
actually is happening most of the work
实际上，
I'm doing is not about here's the
我所做的大部分工作并不是在讲解
science here's why you need to do it
科学原理，也不是在告诉你为什么你需要这样做。
here's what's happening in your brain
这就是你大脑中正在发生的事情，
here's the food list it would be so easy
这是食物清单。
if that's what it were we are human
如果事情真像清单上写的那样简单就好了。我们是
beings and we have really complicated
人类，我们与
relationships with food we have history
食物的关系非常复杂。我们
with food we have spiritual attachments
与食物有着历史渊源，我们对食物有精神上的依恋、
to food cultural attachments to food
文化上的依恋、
political ATT beliefs about food and and
政治上的信仰等等。
a lot of us have addictions and
我们中的许多人对
attachments to food that go back a long
食物都有着由来已久的依赖和成瘾。
way so most of it is about helping
所以，大部分工作都是帮助
people understand and and sort of hold
人们理解食物，并在他们改变行为的
their hand through that proc process of
过程中给予他们支持和指导。
whatever is going on in their life is
他们生活中的任何事情也都很
also important so how did you approach
重要。那么，你是如何
that with your patients so in the first
与你的病人进行沟通的呢？在第
in the first interview with somebody I
一次面谈中，我
usually take 90 minutes to two hours
通常会花90分钟到两个小时的时间，在
before we actually begin uh discussing
真正开始讨论
what to do with diet because I really
饮食方案之前，我可能会进行两到三次这样的沟通。因为我真的
want to
想
understand um all of the different
了解所有不同的
pieces of the puzzle not just oh what
方面，而不仅仅是告诉他们“
are you eating here's what you should
你现在吃什么，你应该
eat M that doesn't work for most people
吃什么”。这对大多数人来说行不通，
and because there are going to be
因为总会遇到各种
challenges that come up and if the
挑战。如果沟通得更好…… 越
better I know that person the better I
了解这个人，我就越
can help them through those challenges
能帮助他们克服挑战。
so it's not it's definitely not um it's
所以，我绝对不会
not like I hand them a prescription for
像给他们开个
a diet and send them out the door I love
饮食处方就把他们打发走那样。我喜欢
understanding where people are coming
了解人们的处境，
from they're you know the the challenges
了解
they're facing in their lives and how
他们生活中面临的挑战，以及这些挑战如何影响
that all intersects with their metabolic
他们的代谢
Health their their exercise you know why
健康、运动习惯，比如
are they not exercising um how is their
他们为什么不运动，他们的
sleep how are their relationships who in
睡眠状况如何，人际关系如何，生活中谁
their life is supportive of them
支持他们
changing their diet um is who in their
改变饮食，谁又持
life is skeptical and worried and
怀疑和担忧的态度。
because that could be a major factor for
因为这可能是一个重要因素：
people if one person in the family wants
如果家里有人想
or needs to go on a ketogenic diet for
或需要为了心理健康而进行生酮饮食，
mental health and nobody else in the
而其他
family thinks it's a good idea
家人都不认为这是个好主意，那对
that's really tough for people you
他们来说真的很难。
you've got to plan for all of that and
你必须提前计划好所有这些情况，并进行充分的沟通，比如：
talk it through say okay here are the
好吧，我们
roadblocks we might face how are we
可能会遇到
with these when they come up so I could
这些障碍，当它们出现时，我们该如何应对？我可以举
give many many examples but the
很多例子，但心理治疗，也就是生酮饮食
Psychotherapy the psychology of it is
的心理学原理，才是
why using ketogenic diets to treat
使用生酮饮食治疗
mental health conditions is usually best
心理健康的关键所在。 通常情况下，最好是
team ideally if you can a keto dietician
团队合作，理想情况下，最好能找到一位经验丰富的生酮营养师
or nutrition therapist who's very
或营养治疗师，他们精通
skilled skill at using ketogenic diets
生酮饮食的
designing them and personalizing for
设计和个性化定制，能够满足您的各种饮食需求和喜好，让
whatever you like to eat um so you'll
您
have an enjoyable diverse diet that
拥有丰富多样的饮食，既能
meets your needs and your desires um so
满足您的需求和愿望，
you won't get bored and you'll enjoy the
又不会让您感到乏味，让您真正享受美食。
if you're especially if you're taking
如果您正在服用
medication or have any mental or
药物或存在任何
physical health issues you'll need a
身心健康问题，您还需要一位处方医生，可以是
prescribing professional primary care
初级保健
doctor um or a psychiatrist or both
医生、精神科医生，或者两者都需要，具体取决于您的情况。他们可以帮助
depending what's going on for you to
您
manage the medications and help you
管理药物，并帮助您
through that transition period where
度过过渡期。在这个过渡期，
changing in your physiology that can
您的生理机能会发生很多变化，
sometimes be uncomfortable if you don't
如果没有做好
plan properly um and set the person up
充分的计划和准备，可能会感到不适。此外，您还需要一位
for Success um and a coach a therapist a
教练、治疗
psychologist or a coach to for
师或心理学家，为您提供
motivation and support and it could be a
动力和支持。他/她可以像啦啦队长一样为您加油鼓劲，也可以定期向
you how things are going and and and
您反馈进展情况，帮助
keep you moving forward because the
您不断前进，因为
first few weeks are the hardest and once
最初的几周是最难熬的。
you get past about week three week three
过了大约三周，对
is a real turning point for a lot of
很多人来说，第三周是一个真正的转折点。
people your cells just kind of settle in
你的细胞会逐渐适应
to a new way of operating and it's this
一种新的运作方式，这种
very noticeable shift that takes place
变化非常明显，发生
in people's bodies and brains and that
在人们的身体和大脑中，
many people have never experienced
很多人以前从未经历过。这与
before as it relates to anxiety um what
焦虑有关。
anxiety yes so anxiety uh if you talk to
那么，研究表明生酮饮食在减轻焦虑方面发挥着怎样的作用呢？如果你和
any practitioner who has been using
任何一位
ketogenic diets in their work um whether
在工作中使用生酮饮食的医生交谈，无论
it's a a psychiatric practitioner or a
是精神科医生还是
medical practitioner there are a couple
内科医生，
of things they'll tell you that are most
他们都会告诉你生
ketogenic diet one is reduced anxiety
酮饮食最显著的两大益处：一是减轻焦虑，
and the other is mental Clarity so most
二是提升思维清晰度。大多数
people will experience tremendous
人在开始生酮饮食后的
within three days to three weeks of
三到三周内，焦虑就会显著减轻。
starting a ketogenic diet and the mental
而思维
Clarity is is one of those things that
清晰度的提升，
you hear almost from almost everybody so
几乎每个人都会提到。至于
the anxiety is uh remember we're talking
焦虑，记住，我们谈论的是
about this roller coaster those stress
过山车，压力
hormones are on a roller coaster life
激素就像过山车一样，生活
can cause stress and stress can
会带来压力，而压力会
unbalance your your Chemistry there's no
扰乱你的身体化学平衡。 这一点
question about that but your food can
毋庸置疑，但你的食物也会造成这种影响，
also do that your diet can also
你的饮食也会扰乱
unbalance your stress hormones so and
你的压力激素平衡。
this is comes back to your question
这就回到了
about you know life stressors you don't
你关于生活压力源的问题，你
want to ignore those because they still
不能忽视它们，因为它们仍然
count and they're still affecting your
重要，仍然会影响你的新陈代谢。
metabolic Health stress raises your
健康压力会提高你的
cortisol levels and cortisol levels are
皮质醇水平，而皮质醇水平过高
dangerous for long-term brain health
对大脑健康有害。
High cortisol levels most mental health
大多数精神健康
conditions come along with disregulated
问题都伴有大脑
or poor regulation of cortisol levels in
中皮质醇水平失调或调节不良，
the brain and too much cortisol can over
过多的皮质醇会随着
time damage the brain including uh the
时间的推移损害大脑，包括
hippocampus which is the brain's
海马体——大脑的
learning and memory Center so Str add
学习和记忆中心。因此，压力源是
whether it's coming from inside the body
来自
from the foods you're eating or outside
你吃的食物（体内）还是来自
the body from your life both of those
你的生活（体外），两者都
need to be addressed not just the
需要解决，而不仅仅是
dietary stress there's some studies that
饮食压力。
I just found um a 2023 systemic review
我刚刚找到一些研究，一篇2023年的系统性综述
examine the E efficacy of low
探讨了低
carbohydrate ketogenic diets and
碳水化合物生酮饮食
treating mood and anxiety disorders the
治疗情绪和焦虑症的疗效。该
review highlighted potential benefits
综述强调了潜在的益处，
but emphasized the ne necessity for
但也强调了进行
randomized control trials to establish
随机对照试验以得出
definitive conclusions that was the
明确结论的必要性。该综述由
Cambridge University press and slightly
剑桥大学出版社出版，内容略有
separate to that um on serious mental
不同。 关于严重的精神
illnesses I think you talk about this in
疾病，我想你在
your work as well a 2024 pilot study
工作中也谈到过这一点。斯坦福大学医学院在2024年进行的一项试点研究
investigated the effects of a ketogenic
调查了生酮
diet on participants with schizophrenia
饮食对精神分裂症
and bipolar and participants reported
和双相情感障碍患者的影响，结果显示参与者的
improvements in energy sleep mood and
精力、睡眠、情绪和
quality of life suggesting that
生活质量都有所改善，这表明
ketogenic diet May stabilize brain
生酮饮食可能有助于稳定
functions in serious mental illnesses as
严重精神疾病患者的大脑功能。这真的很
well really really fascinating really
有意思，真的非常有意思。
fascinating I never really thought about
我以前从未真正考虑过生
the ketogenic diet's impact on my mental
酮饮食对我的心理
health I used to think I be honest the
健康的影响。说实话，我以前认为
reason I do it is um helps me become
我这样做是因为它能帮助我
more focused
更专注，
it changes my body composition and
改变我的身体成分，而且对
really at the end of the year for me or
我来说，在年末或
at the start of the year it's a nice way
年初，这是一种很好的重置方式。
I see it I want to come into the year
我是这么看的，我希望在新的一年里
feeling good and strong and focused so I
感觉良好、精力充沛、注意力集中，所以我
January time every year with my partner
每年圣诞节、新年和一月份都会和我的伴侣一起进行生酮饮食。
um but I never really considered the
但我从未真正考虑过它的
downstream consequences things like
后续影响，比如
mental health and those other things but
心理健康等等。不过现在想想，这很有道理。
it it makes sense we have a closing
我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个结束语，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，而下一位
guest not knowing who they're leaving it
嘉宾并不知道是谁。
and the question that's been left for
留给
you is what would you say to someone who
你的问题是，你会对那些
wanted to have less regret and more
希望在临终前少些遗憾、多些
contentment and peace on their
满足与平静的人说些什么？
deathbed I'm trying to think about what
我正在思考，就我
for myself personally what I would have
个人而言，我会
regretted
后悔什么。
um you know you might want me to say
嗯，你知道，你可能希望我说
that I would have regretted not having
我会后悔没有
written this book and that's true but
写这本书，这没错，但说
honestly it's about finding a really
实话，这本书是关于如何在生活中找到一段真正健康美好的
good healthy relationship in your life I
关系。我的
mean if I hadn't accomplished that in my
意思是，如果我一生中没能做到这一点，
life I would have more regrets than not
我会比没
writing this
写这
book Thank you thank you for writing
本书更后悔。谢谢你写了
this book because it's such a
这本书，因为它对
understood link between the things we
我们
put in our mouth and the impact it has
吃进嘴里的东西和它对我们
on our mind holistically and I don't
整体心理的影响之间这种鲜为人知的联系进行了如此全面的分析。我
think enough people especially if we
认为，尤其是在我们
think back decades even thought to
回顾几十年前的时候，很少有人真正思考过要
really uncover this sort of link I never
揭示这种联系。我
I think before even starting this
想，甚至在开始这个
podcast never really understood the
播客之前，我从未真正理解过
concept of metabolic and metabolic
代谢和代谢
Psychiatry and that there was an
精神病学的概念，也从未意识到这
association between the two the great
两者之间存在关联。
thing about your book is that you don't
你的书最棒的地方在于，你不需要
need to be a scientist to understand it
是科学家也能读懂它，
it's clearly written for people like me
它显然是为像我这样不懂科学的人而写的。 我对
of Science and um medicine and
科学、医学和
Psychiatry but are able to learn in
精神病学有着深刻的理解，但
advance the decisions we make just by
仅仅通过阅读您的书，就能提前了解我们即将做出的决定。这本书
Smash Hit for so many people I was
对很多人来说都非常畅销。我
looking at some of the reviews earlier
之前看过一些评论，
on and people really really love it you
大家都非常喜欢它。这本书是您
wrote it you published it this year
今年
January January January and uh I highly
一月出版的。我强烈
recommend anyone that is intrigued by
推荐任何对
any of the subject matters that we spoke
我们今天讨论的任何主题感兴趣的人都
about today to go and get a copy I'll
去买一本，
link it below um and it has some
链接在下面。书的封底有一些
extraordinary people on the back who
非常杰出的人物，其中一些
some of which I've interviewed at least
我采访过，至少有
one of which I've interviewed um in
一位是
Jason um is there anything else you
杰森。关于这本书的目标读者，您还有什么
wanted to say about who this book is for
想说的吗？是的，
yeah I mean I really want people with
我真心希望这本书能帮助那些有
mental health conditions even if they
心理健康问题的人，即使他们
think they've tried everything if you
认为自己已经尝试过所有方法。如果
know if you're willing to try one more
您愿意再尝试一次，
thing hope is on the menu a powerful
希望就在眼前。这是一个强有力的
plan to improve mood overcome anxiety
计划，可以改善情绪，克服焦虑
and protect memory for a lifetime of
，保护记忆力，从而拥有终生
optimal mental health thank you so much
最佳的心理健康。非常感谢
for the work that you do thank you very
您所做的工作。谢谢。 非常感谢
much Stephen for your
斯蒂芬的
work do you know that 80% of New Year's
工作。你知道吗？80%的新年
resolutions fail by February it's
计划在二月份就失败了。这是
because we focus too much on the end
因为我们太关注最终
goal and we forget the small daily
目标，而忽略了那些
actions that actually move us forward
真正推动我们前进的日常小行动。
also easy not to do in life it's easy to
生活中，那些容易做到的行动也容易被忽略。
save a dollar so it's also easy not to
省下一美元很容易，所以也很容易放弃
making one small Improvement each day
每天做出一点小小的改进。
one tiny step in the right direction has
朝着正确的方向迈出一小步，
a big difference over time and that is
日积月累就会产生巨大的影响。这就是“
the 1% mindset which is why we created
1%思维”。这也是我们创建“
the 1% diary a 90day journal designed to
1%日记”的原因——一本为期90天的日记，旨在
help you stay consistent and focus on
帮助你保持自律，专注于
the small wins and make real progress
小小的胜利，并随着时间的推移取得真正的进步。
over time it also gives you access to
它还能让你加入“
the 1% community a space where you can
1%社群”，一个可以让你
stay accountable motivated inspired
保持自律、充满动力和灵感，并与
along with many others on the same
许多其他志同道合的人一起踏上这段
Journey we launched the 1% diary in
旅程的空间。我们在11月推出了“1%日记”，
November and it sold out so now we're
并且售罄了。现在我们
doing a second drop join the wait list
进行第二次发售。请访问theeddiary.com加入候补名单，
first to know as soon as it's back in
一旦有货，你就会第一时间收到通知。
stock I'll put the link below
链接如下。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦